■
字幕來源：射手網
后期：筆?·Lee    Sung1219
海角擒兇
狼來了
Here come the wolves.
哦  瓶頸路段  羅斯福應該聽說過這里
Uh-oh. Bottleneck. Mr. Roosevelt should hear of this.
對不起  希望你沒受傷
I'm sorry. Hope you didn't hurt yourself.
我朋友已說對不起
My friend says he's sorry.
好的
Okay.
這顯示金發女郎可影響國家安危
That shows what a blonde can do to hold up national defense.
好小子
Nice, pleasant guy.
是一百塊
Man ! Gee, a hundred bucks.
他們總是這樣的
So that's what they look like.
他去了哪里
Where'd he go ?
不知道  不知他叫什么名字
I don't know. Uh-- I wonder what his name is.
且慢  我在信封上見到
I saw it on the envelope. Uh...
富禮  對了  是福禮
Fry. That's it. Fry.
富禮你怎知道我的名字
Fry. How do you know my name ?
你何需介懷我如何知你的名字
What do you care how I know your name ?
我在你丟的信封上看見
I saw it on one of the envelopes you dropped.
這是屬于你的
Here's something that belongs to you.
是油漆房
The paint shop !
會像炸藥爆炸
It'll go up like dynamite! Here. Take this one.
我也要救火  拿個滅火筒給我
What about me ? Don't I get to play too ? You get another. Right!
我看見那兩個小伙子
So I see these two kids.
我對他們呼叫  滅火花灑失靈
And I yell at them, ''The sprinklers are busted.
慘劇隨即發生
The whole shootin' match will go up.''
他倆沖入火場
And they run right in, the both of them.
當我回頭望時  最后目睹的
And the last thing I saw when I looked back...
是其中一人將滅火筒交給另一人
was one kid give the extinguisher to the other kid,
然后更是一片火海
and then it was just like all hell comes up.
這是我目睹的一切
That's all I see.
附近有其他人嗎
Was there anybody else around?
沒有  只有那兩人
No. Just the two kids:
那拿著滅火筒及遞筒給他的人
the poor kid with the extinguisher and the one who give it to him.
謝謝你  羅渣士  多謝你幫忙
Thank you, Rogers. We appreciate all you've done.
我們不再耽誤你的時間了
We needn't keep you any longer now.
快去醫治你的手傷吧
Take care of those hands.
下一位是誰
Who've you got next ?
有一位叫巴利堅尼的人在等候
There's a fellow Barry Kane waiting.
召巴利堅尼進來
Send Barry Kane in.
巴利堅尼
Barry Kane !
你不必緊張
All right. Just take it easy.
我們只是問你幾個問題
We only want to ask you a couple of questions.
是例行的查問
A routine checkup.
我會盡我所能去幫你
Well, I want to do anything I can to help.
好極  可否告訴我們
Sure. Now, suppose you tell us
火警發生時你身在何處
where you were when the fire started.
我是最先沖入火場的人
Well, I was one of the first to rush in.
當時滅火系統失靈
The sprinkler systems weren't working.
有誰跟你一起入火場
Who else was with you ?
只有我和一個叫富禮的人
There was just myself, a fellow named Fry and my friend...
還有我朋友簡美臣繼續
Ken Mason.
富禮將滅火筒遞給我
Go on. Fry handed me an extinguisher.
我沖向火團
and I started running toward the fire.
我將滅火筒交給簡
I gave it to Ken.
然后  他
And then he--
你輕松點  問完了
Okay. Take it easy. That's all.
你到外面稍候  我們會再需要你
Just stick around for a while. We may need you.
去找富禮
Send for Fry.
去找一個叫富禮的男子
Get hold of a fellow called Fry.
他們怎樣做  問你很多問題
What'd they do, ask you a lot of questions ?
你目睹一切  實在很難過
Hardly any. Gee, it's awful tough going. seeing it happen in front of you.
對  很難過
Yeah, it is tough.
簡美臣是你的好友嗎
Ken Mason was your pal, too. wasn't he ?
是
Yeah.
他已婚嗎  不  他跟母親同住
Was he married ? No. He was living with his mother.
她一定會很難過了
Must be pretty tough on her.
對不起  我遲些再找你
Sorry, fellows. I'll see you later.
美臣太太
Hello, Mrs. Mason.
他們  他們不讓我見他
They-- They wouldn't let me see him.
實在很難相信  事情發生得很快
It's awful hard to believe. It happened so quick.
為什么  只是今晨
Why, only this morning-- Please !
請你別再提此事
Please don't talk about it now.
我有什么可以幫你
Anything I can do ? Could I get you something ?
不  多謝你  暫時不必了
No. No, thank you. Not now.
或許喝點拔蘭地吧
Maybe some brandy.
那可憐的心靈怎么了
How is the poor, dear soul ?
你是指美臣太太  她很傷心
If you mean Mrs. Mason, she's feeling bad.
她當然會傷心  你知嗎
Ah, well. She's every reason to.
他們竟不讓她見他
Do you know what ? They wouldn't even let her see him.
是她的獨子啊
Her only son.
對  我知道
Yes. I know.
我告訴她  她有權堅持要見兒子
I told her to insist on seeing him.
我說我會堅持  她叫我滾
I told her I would, and she as good as told me to get out !
我只不過想幫她  可憐的心靈
Me ! That was only tryin' to help. The poor, dear soul.
可否告訴我何處可找到拔蘭地
I think you can help,
喝點酒可幫她解憂愁
if you'll get some brandy.
年青人  你跟我來
You come with me, young man.
我家里存放著一點酒
I have a little in the house.
美臣太太  對不起  打擾你了
Sorry to bother you, Mrs. Mason,
我們正在找尋巴利堅尼  他
but we're looking for Barry Kane. Do you know him ?
他目前不在這里嗎
He isn't here right now. is he ?
工廠的人說可在這里找到他
They told us at the plant we might be able to find him here.
他不在  你要找他是關于什么
Well... what do you want to see him about ?
他惹上天大的麻煩
He's in pretty bad trouble,
是什么  我想知道
lady. What ? I'd like to know.
他涉及工廠的火警
He was mixed up with that fire at the factory.
我  我不明白
I-- I don't understand.
我們有也很多事情不明白
There are a lot of things we don't understand either.
巴利為何會牽涉此事
But how is Barry involved in it ?
那滅火筒  似乎并非是意外
That fire extinguisher. Seems it wasn't just an accident.
巴利遞交的
It turns out that the extinguisher Barry Kane handed
滅火筒裝滿電油
your son... was filled with gasoline. Oh !
你一定可以幫到我們
You ought to be able to help us.
請提供線索  讓我們找到堅尼
Give us a lead on this guy Kane.
太太  這是我們到來搜查的原因
Yeah. That's why we want to look around. Well-- Why--
我目前未能說些什么
I can't talk about it now. I--
對不起  但你應知道
Yeah. Sorry, but, you see, there was--
若我是你  便不會給她太大壓力
I wouldn't give her too much of that. It often makes people weepy.
若再提起便會令她泣不成聲
I know it affects me-- Yes, I've got to hurr back.
摩亞太太  我要回去了  謝謝你
Thank you very much.
試一口吧  會令你舒服些的
Try some of this, Mrs. Mason. It'll make you feel better.
剛才有兩位探員到來
There were two detectives just here.
他們在找你
They were looking for you. For me ?
我猜他們要問我一些問題
I guess they wanted to ask more questions.
我說我幫不了忙  來  試試看
I said I'd help.Here. Try this.
不  他們是要拘捕你
No. That wasn't it. They wanted to arrest you.
他們說你遞交的
They said that the fire extinguisher that you handed to Kenneth...
滅火筒裝滿電油
was filled with gasoline.
是你殺死他
That you killed him.
我殺死他
That I killed--
他們瘋了嗎  我怎會這樣做
Why, are they crazy ? Why would I want to do a thing--
我怎會  簡是我最好的朋友
Ken was my best friend !
他們有否問過富禮關于那滅火筒
Haven't they talked to Fry about the extinguisher ?
他們說工廠沒有雇用這個人
They said that there was no such man employed at the plant.
但我見過他  見過兩次
Why, I saw him ! I saw him twice !
簡見過他  我們在火場見過面
Ken saw him too ! He was with us at the fire.
他將滅火筒遞給我  簡在開玩笑
He handed me the extinguisher. Ken said,
說要幫忙
''Don't I get to play too ?''
于是我將滅炎筒交給他
He was kidding. I handed it to him.
我肯定富禮當時和我們一起
Fry was right there with us, I'm sure !
他一定知道里面有電油的
Why, he must have known there was gasoline in it.
他一定會知道
He must have known !
他跟我們一起站著觀看
He stood right there with us and watched, that--
請你走吧
Please go.
你不相信我嗎
Don't you believe me ?
你認為我有份參與此事
Do you think I had something to do with this ?
我沒有對警方講任何說話
I didn't tell the police anything.
我不知  實在太混淆及可怕了
Oh, I don't know ! It's all so confused and so terrible.
我不明他們
I don't know what they're talking about !
為何不去找富禮
Why don't they get this fellow Fry ?
你最好快走
You'd better go.
好的  我會走
All right. I'll go.
我要去找富禮  定要找到他
I've got to find Fry,
否則簡不會是最后一個犧牲者
or Ken won't be the last one to die.
他一定在里面  我看見他走進去
I saw him go in the back way.
很悅耳什么
Catchy.
你吹的那調子
What ? That tune you're whistling.
我根本不知自己在吹口哨
Oh, I didn't even know I was whistling.
這表示你很快樂
You must be pretty happy.
顯而易見  你無憂無慮
Easy to see there's nothin' on your mind.
一定是我"小兒"我感覺到是他
Oops. That must have been Junior.Felt like him.
"小兒"
Junior ?
對  剛才那些敲打聲
Yeah. that rock.
我從羅省至連奴治路認識所有人
I know every one from Los Angeles to Reno.
駕駛貨車實在是艱苦的工作
Tough job, driving a truck.
今晚有其他最新消息嗎
Got any other hot news tonight ?
我從未想過會如此艱辛
I never realized how tough it was before.
艱辛  你應可忍受
The tough part, you can take that.
你只不過感到無聊
It's the monotony that gets you.
我一直希望脫離這駕車生涯
I been thinking I'm gonna get out of this trucking game.
為何不
Why don't you ?
我鄰居對我妻說每天要吃?餐
One of the neighbors told my wife it's stylish to eat three meals a day.
你結了婚嗎
- You married ?
沒有
- Nope.
你繼續吹口哨吧
Go ahead and whistle.
什么事令你困擾
That thing bother you ?
為何會這樣
What's doin' it ?
用這疊報紙墊著它
Here. Stick this wad of paper in there, will you ?
滅火筒實在很有用
It's a pretty good thing to have around,
是駕車必備的設施
one of these extinguishers.
早幾天  有部運菜的貨車
I wouldn't be without one. Now, take the other day.
在這里翻車  就在這里
A big truck turns over right down here.
瀉出的電油會令貨車著火
The gasoline catches, and she goes up like a matchbox.
司機女友被困車內若沒有滅火筒
A friend of the driver's gets caught in her.
司機將要送
If the driver hadn't had an extinguisher,
女友葬身火海了
his pal would have been fried alive.
我沒眼見到意外
I didn't see it happen. I never see anything happen.
亦未聽到任何消息
I don't even hear about anything, e
我妻只會跟我說棒球賽
xcept when my wife tells me the moving pictures.
她喜歡花這些錢
That's the way she spends the money:
看棒球和買新帽
moving pictures and new hats.
她愛買新帽然后戴著去看棒球
Buys a hat so she can go to the picture show so she can take it off.
而我卻無從反對
No, sir. I haven't got anything to whistle about.
老友  你來自何地
Where are you from, bud ?
洛杉磯
Uh, Los Angeles.
你在那里工作
Tough. You work down there ?
對  以前是
Yeah. Well, I did.
是什么工作
What doin' ?
我是在飛機制造工作的
I was workin' in an airplane factory.
人們說那是一份優差
They say that's pretty good.
你不屬于軍部的嗎
I was wondering why you weren't in the army.
是
Yeah.
事關國防  他們對雇員要求嚴格
They're particular about the fellows they hire in those defense plants.
這亦算正確
That's no more than right.
若雇員不小心便會令工廠爆炸
They gotta be careful they don't get blown up.
對
Yeah.
我知道若雇員有案底
I understand if a fellow had any police record,
便不會被錄用  是嗎
no job. Is that right ?
我不知道
Oh. I don't know.
老友  可否代我控制方向盤
Hey, buddy. Hold the wheel a while, will you,
我要點煙  我是個煙鬼
while I animate this thing. I'm a nicotine addict.
小心啊  別越過白線
Hey, watch it, bud ! Stay on this side of the white line.
到了史比維后  你在何處下車
Where do you wanna get off when we get to Springville ?
到了市中心  隨時讓我下車吧
It doesn't matter. Drop me in the middle of town.
史比維便是市中心了
The minute you get to Springville, you're in the middle of the town.
那是個小鎮  很快便駛過
The next minute, the place is a memory.
整個鎮沒有什么建筑物
Whole town isn't a city block long.
你要到那個農場嗎
You're goin' to one of those big ranches outside, aren't you ?
是
- Yeah.
你要到那里  我便送你到門口
- I'd be glad to drop you off at whatever one you want.
到了  春天農場
That's it ! Deep Springs Ranch.
唏  那農場很大
Hey ! Say, that's a whale of a big place.
你要去那里找工作嗎
Got a chance of a job there ?
是  我看是的
Yeah. I think so.
你定會喜歡  天氣怡人
You ought to like it. Nice climate.
警察  可能有事發生
The police ! Maybe something's happened !
我有話跟你說  下車
I'd like to talk with you out here. Yeah. Sure. officer !
好的  你留在這里  我一會兒回來
Stay here. I'll be right back.
老朋友  上車吧  已經行了
Hey, bud ! Come on. Everything's fixed.
晚安  警官
Good night, Officer.
你會料到如此嗎
Can you imagine a thing like that ?
那警察響起警號追截
Cop, sirens, the whole works !
原因是我的車尾燈壞了
One of my taillights went out.
這是駕車生涯的悲歌
That's the trucking game for you in a nutshell.
通知各公路巡警
Calling all highway patrolmen.
請留意一個叫巴利堅尼的男子
Be on lookout for a man named Barry Kane.
最后出現地點是99號公路
Last seen on Highway 99.
深棕色頭發  藍眼睛
He has dark brown hair, blue eyes,
身高約高六尺二寸  沒有戴帽
height about six feet two, no hat,
年約二十五歲
around 25 years old.
通知各公路巡警
Calling all highway patrolmen. Calling all highway patrolmen.
你好嗎  法蘭富禮先生在嗎
How do you do ? Is, uh, Mr. Frank Fry here ?
這是杜賓的農場
No, this is Mr. Tobin's ranch.
我可否跟杜賓先生談談
Oh. Uh, could I speak to Mr. Tobin ?
請稍后  你在這里等我
Well, I'll see. Just a minute. You wait here, please.
我們接你的球
There. We've got the ball.
主人  有位先生要見你
Throw it to me. Ayoung man to see you. sir.
拋給我  乖女孩
Throw it to me. Where is Daddy's girl ?
艾黛  你說什么
What did you say, Adele ?
有位年青男士要找富禮先生
Who wants to see me ? Ayoung man, sir. He came to ask for a Mr. Fr.
請你叫他來
Oh. Well. Have him come out here, will you ?
將球拋給我
Yes, sir. Throw me the ball. Throw me the ball.
爺爺來了
Here comes your granddaddy.
杜賓先生會見你  請跟我來
Mr. Tobin will see you. Follow me, please. Thank you.
你好嗎  我是查理杜賓
How do you do ? I'm Charles Tobin.
她是我女兒  布朗太太
This is my daughter, Mrs. Brown.
你好嗎  你好
How do you do ?Well,
別介意我衣著隨便
I'm not gonna ask you to excuse the informality of this costume.
我們春天農場是很隨便的
We're all informal out here at Deep Springs Ranch.
是我們這里的規矩
That's one of the rules. I see.
我帶蘇絲出去  以免妨礙你
Want me to take Suzy with me ?
不  蘇絲不會妨礙我們
No, Suzy isn't gonna disturb us at all.
讓她在這里玩  我會照顧她了
Just let her play right here. I'll see she doesn't fall in the pool.
好的
All right.
我們到那邊去  好嗎
Well, shall we sit out here ?
好的
Yes. sir.
天朗氣清  最適宜戶外活動
It seems a shame to go indoors on such a beautiful day.
是啊
Yes, it does.
你有事要見我嗎
You wanted to see me about something ?
是  我要找一個叫法蘭富禮的人
Yes, sir. I'm looking for a man named Fry. Frank Fry.
我在洛杉磯遇到他  我知道他住在這里
I met him up in Los Angeles. I understand he lives here.
不
Oh, no. No.
富禮
Fry, huh ?
法蘭富禮  我不認識這名字的人
Frank Fry. I'm afraid I don't know anybody by that name.
我似曾聽過這名字
Wait a minute. Fry. I've heard that name somewhere.
但沒有印象
I just don't seem to be able to place it.
以前有個這名字的人
Uh, there used to be a fellow... with a name something like that,
在這里工作
worked around here.
不  他不是富禮
No. No. It wasn't Fry.
你可以找錯地址了
Well, I'm afraid you found the wrong address.
或許是你這里的工人
Well, it couldn't be one of the cowhands or somebody who's working ?
不會  我記得所有工人的名字
No, I know the names of all my men.
等等  是我的鄰居
Wait a minute. My next door neighbor--
我鄰居距離這里二十里
''Next door neighbor.'' He lives 20 miles from here !
他可能認識你的朋友讓
But he may know.
我致電給他
I'll telephone him.
不  不必勞煩了
Oh, no, please don't.
絕對不會  你跑了這么遠的路
No, no ! You look as though you've had a hard journey.
我不想你白走一趟
Too bad if you came all this way for nothing.
你稍候  我們起碼也要搞清楚
If you'll just wait, we can find out.
你要照顧蘇絲  別讓她掉進泳池
Will you see that Suzy doesn't fall into the pool ? Yes, sir. Thank you.
唏  過來
Hey. Come here.
過來
Come over here.
你要玩球嗎  將球拋給我
Oh, so you're a ball player, are you ? Throw me the ball.
給我吧  拋給我
Let me have it. Come on. Throw me the ball.
對了  拋另一個給我
Throw me the other one. Come on.
來吧  拋給我  好極了
Throw it to me. Come on. Give me the ball.
我拋回給你
That's fine. Fine ! Now, I'll throw it back.
你去哪里  別這樣做
Where are you goin' ? Uh-oh. Don't do that.
放回原位
Leave those where they are. Leave them right there.
"致法蘭富禮"
"勞煩查理杜賓轉交"
"已辦妥  在梳打鎮會合尼爾信"
"法蘭字"
你要乖呀  快放回原位
Wanna be a good girl ? Put these back where you found them.
叔叔叫你將它放回原位
No, no, Suzy. The gentleman says put them back where you found them.
你要小心保管
The gentleman knows that you must be careful
不屬于你的信件
with letters that don't belong to you.
我并非偏心
Probably I'm prejudiced, but it seems to me...
蘇絲確實很可愛
that Suzy is a pretty cute young lady.
她很可愛  法蘭富禮在哪里
Yeah. she's great. Where's Frank Fry ?
你的記憶力一定有問題了
Really, you must do something about that memory of yours.
剛才你看過富禮給我的電報
It wasn't a minute ago that you read a telegram that Fry sent me,
他說正在前往梳打鎮途中
and it said that he was on his way to Soda City.
你記得嗎
Don't you remember that ?
梳打市在哪里
Where's Soda City ?
我未曾詳細查核過
Well, I haven't given it much thought, but I wouldn't imagine...
梳打市已廢置應已在地圖上消失
there'd be an overabundance of Soda Cities on the map.
但總會有辦法可找到的
You could find out some way.
來自洛杉磯的最新消息
bringing you last-minute headlines.
史劍活飛機廠
Los Angeles. The fire in the Stewart Aircraft Works
火警中有一人喪生
in which one man was killed,
傷者眾多  損失超過五十萬
many injured and half a million dollars' worth of damage caused,
肯定是被陰謀破壞
has been definitely set down to sabotage.
警方正追尋爆炸之兇巴利堅尼
Police have traced the incendiary blaze to Barry Kane,
是飛機廠的前任
former--
你不想再聽吧
Don't want any more of that.
你定會對描述自己感到沉悶
Think you'd be rather bored with the descriptions of yourself.
你或許不會覺得煩厭
Or maybe you never get tired of them. Well, I am by this time.
但我整個早上也在聽這些報導
I've been listening to those reports all morning.
你已知道我了  究竟如何
You knew me. What about it ?
我相信你已知道一切
Oh, quite a lot about it, Mr. Kane. You ought to know that.
你已舉世聞名  何必保持低調
You've become too famous to remain so modest.
可否告訴我一件事  可以
Tell me one thing.
你為何要維護法蘭富禮
Why are you covering up Frank Fry ?
你為何要如此對待這人
What's a man like you in this for ?
年青人  我不知你在說什么
Young man, I don't know what you're talking about.
我看你是知道的  他是個破壞者
I think maybe you do !
收受金錢殺戮美國人
Frank Fry is a saboteur who doesn't mind killing Americans for money.
堅尼先生  你要自己小心
You must watch yourself, Mr. Kane !
我這樣說是為你好
I'm telling you this for your own benefit,
你會招惹很多麻煩的
but you have the makings of an outstanding bore.
杜賓  你也不能置身事外
You can't get away with this.
我不阻止你  其他人也會的
Even if I don't stop you, others will.
你這類人是不能在國內安枕的
A man like you can't last in a country like this.
好漂亮的說話
Very pretty speech.
有朝氣  有熱誠  有理想
Youthful, passionate, idealistic.
我已通知警方
You see, I've already sent for the police.
你別嚇唬我  你也有關連的
You can't bluff me. You're hooked, and you know it.
我提醒你  你是個逃犯而我不是
Must I remind you that you are the fugitive and not I ?
我是個廣受愛戴的顯赫公民
I'm a prominent citizen, widely respected.
你是個重犯
You are an obscure young workman...
是個逃亡的工人
wanted for the committing of an extremely unpopular crime.
你認為警方會相信誰
Which of us do you think the police will believe ? Hmm ?
你定以為我是個窮困的主人家了
Oh, you must think me a very poor host, Mr. Kane.
要喝杯什么飲品嗎
Now, don't you feel that a long, cold drink is indicated ?
我已清楚你要跟我講的說話
I found out everything you're gonna tell me.
我要離去  獨自應付未來
I'll have to do the rest by myself.
你意思是要離開我們
You wish to leave us ?
艾黛  堅尼先生要走了
Adele, Adele! Mr. Kane is going!
對不起  請你停步
I'm sorry. You'll stop, please.
這是什么  水槍
What does that shoot ? Water ?
我恐怕會有子彈
Bullets. I'm afraid.
你別憂心沖沖地離去吧  堅尼
You shouldn't be so anxious to leave us.
你傷害我們的感情
You'll hurt our feelings.
你令我難以抗拒你的邀請
You make it very hard for me to refuse your invitations.
蘇絲  來吧
- Suzy, come on.
不  蘇絲  過來
- No, no, Suzy ! Come here.
來吧  蘇絲  你知要去何處嗎
Hello, Suzy. You know where we're going ?
我們要去騎牛牛
For a piggyback ride. You like piggyback rides ?
祖  快去追他
Dick, Joe! Get after him !
追他  快
Hurry up ! Get him ! Get after him ! Hurry up !
繼續走
Come on. Get going.
等等  你不能這樣帶我走的
You can't take me away like this.
別教我們做事  快走吧
Don't tell us what we can't do, chum. Go on. Get started !
我告訴你  你要去拘捕他
You gotta get him ! Just because he's got a big ranch...
他擁有一間大農場泳池及大屋
and a fancy pool doesn't mean
你便認為他是個好人嗎
he's a nice guy !
你為何不去了解他所做的一切
Find out the things he's been doing ! Sure. We know all about that.
我們已了解一切  你走吧  那寶寶收藏那些信件
Just come on along. The baby had the letters !
蘇絲當然會樂于合作
Oh, Suzy would be only too glad to cooperate,
但她要過幾個月才能提供協助
but it'll be months before she'll be of any assistance.
不  蘇絲  不是給你的
No, no, Suzy. Those are not for Suzy. Those are for the gentleman.
是給這位先生的
All right, let's go.
我們要去哪里
Where are we goin' ?
要帶你去見識一下本州的監獄
We're gonna let you get an idea of the county jail.
這是西部最好的監獄
You won't find it the best in the West.
在這里住兩天無傷大雅
But it won't hurt you
待洛杉磯警方來接你吧
'til they come up from Los Angeles for you.
你沒有手令是不能拘留我的
You can't hold me without a warrant. Chum.
我不是說過  別教我做事啊
Do I have to keep askin' you not to tell us what we can't do ?
我要向你解釋  沒有時間了
I'm tryin' to explain ! There isn't time !
有的是時間  你別擔心
Time's the one thing you don't need to worry about.
若找到個好律師
You'll have it to burn.
你可過二十年平靜舒適的生活
You'll have 20 years, if you get the right lawyer.
否則  你的一生便就此告終
If you don't, you'll have all the time there is.
有何不妥  為何在此停車
- What's wrong ? What's holding us up ?
前面有輛貨車阻擋去路
- Truck blockin' the road.
似乎在換輪胎
Looks like they're changin'a tire.
有香煙嗎  有
Got a cigarette ? Sure. All you want.
你好嗎  老友
Hiya, bud !
什么事
Hey, what's the matter ?
他往那邊逃了他在那兒
There he goes ! There he is !
有人嗎
Hello there.
我遇上雷暴  全身都濕透了
Hello. I got caught in this storm. I'm pretty wet, I'm afraid.
不如進來  先抹干身體吧
Maybe you'd like to come inside and get dry.
你將車留在路上嗎  何不將它駛來這里
Did you leave your car down on the road ? Put it in the shed.
任由它被風吹雨打不大好啊
It won't do it any good standing in the rain.
我沒有汽車的
I don't have any car.
你可說我是徒步旅行
You might say I'm traveling by thumb.
徒走  對  我是搭順風車的
By thumb ? Yeah. I'm a hitchhiker.
我認為這是
Oh, I see. I've always thought that was
了解民風的好方法
the best way to learn about this country,
亦是測試美國民心的妙法
and the surest test of the American heart.
對  我猜是的
Yes, I guess it is.
你去火爐旁烘干衣服吧
Will you go to the fire and dr your clothes ?
謝謝
Thanks.
將衣服掛起來會快干一點
They'd dry more quickly
你穿上我的衣服吧
if you put on something of mine.
不  謝謝了  這樣可以了
Oh, no, thanks ! This is fine.
我們要加添柴枝  好嗎
We could do with another log on the fire. Would you ?
當然
Why, sure.
你要留下來待暴雨過去
You must stay until this blows over.
不會誤你太久的
It won't detain you long.
秋天的暴雨通常不會持久
These autumn storms are short.
令人衣衫盡濕  但維時短暫
They yield to none in wetness, but they are short. Yes. I--
我應警告你  那些木是很重的
I should have warned you. Those logs are heavier than you'd think.
我也常常丟在地上
I drop them constantly.
對  很重
Yes, they are heavy.
我還以為可以一雙后拿起它
I guess I was too smart trying to pick it up with one hand.
幸虧沒有掉在腳上
Good job it didn't land on your foot. That often happens to me.
我常被擊中腳  你真幸運
You're lucky.
對  我很幸運
Yeah. I'm lucky.
我忘了  我叫菲力馬田
Oh, I was forgetting. My name is Philip Martin.
我叫巴利  美臣
Oh, I'm Barry K-- Mason.
美臣  在暴雨中得你光臨寒舍
I'm glad you found yourself near here, Mr. Mason, when the storm came.
在雨水打在屋頂的時刻
It's a pleasant thing to have a guest sharing the fire
能遇到你這貴賓實在是樂事
when the rain is beating on the roof.
你在這里獨居嗎
- You live here alone, sir ?
是  但我并非這般想法
- Yes, except I don't think of it in that way.
聲音對我來說是光芒  是色彩
You see, sounds are my lights and my colors.
例如說音樂  我作了些樂曲
My music, for example. I compose a little.
不必人言  我也覺得很美妙
And there is nobody to tell me that the results are anything but brilliant,
因此我樂得自娛  活得開心
so I live in a comfortable glow of self-appreciation.
我也樂意演奏別人的作品
##
毫無疑問  你也會樂于聆聽的
Undoubtedly, you'd prefer listening to them.
我以前中學時是玩敲擊樂哭的
I used to play the triangle in our high school
但已是很久以前的事了
band a long time ago.
你竟疏于
Oh, that's too bad. It's unfortunate
練習敲擊樂器
when you get out of practice on the triangle.
鋼琴簡直是上天對我的恩賜
The piano is a boon to me.
鋼琴不知你是盲的
The piano can't know that you're blind,
它不會令你尷尬  不會令你難過
so it doesn't embarrass you by trying to make things easier for you.
它令你信任它
It does you the compliment to trust you.
英國作曲家狄里斯也是失明的
Delius, the British composer, was blind too.
這是我們唯一相近似的地方
That's our only resemblance.
這是他的"仲夏夜的河畔"
This is his ''Summer Night on the River.''
深入咬蘋果聲  效果很有趣
A very interesting effect: obligato on an apple.
美臣先生  我要向你道歉
Oh, I apologize, Mr. Mason.
我忘記你長途跋涉后很肚餓
I forgot how hungry you must be after your long walk.
等一會  我去替你預備
Just a moment. I'll get something. Oh, no. Thanks.
不  多謝了  我喜歡吃蘋果
This is fine. I-- I like apples.
我也喜歡  留待作甜品吧
So do I. We'll save them for dessert.
晚餐已預備好了
It was all ready, you see.
我常要人提醒我進食
All I needed was a reminder that I was hungry too.
你衣服干透了嗎
Are you dry enough ?
差不多了
Just about. sir.
雨已停了
It stopped raining.
有汽車來嗎
Is that a car coming ?
我猜是兩架失陪了
Two cars, I think.
其中一架是我侄女的  我認得
One car is my niece's. I'd know that motor anywhere.
另一架是陌生的
The other is a stranger to me.
另一車內有兩名男子  那女孩
A couple of men.The girl's
站在車旁指點  似是問路的人
pointing down the road. They must have asked her where to go.
在這國家很易迷途
This is an easy country to lose your way in.
這正是可愛之處
That's one of its charms.
汽車已開走了
They're starting off down the road now.
那女孩正從小徑上來
The girl's coming.
她是我的侄女  來這里陪我
That's my niece. She's been staying with me.
她每年從紐約來陪我一個月
She comes from New York to spend a month with me every year.
這是我最大的樂趣
It's one of my greatest pleasures.
最令我不高興的是她不能久留
Unhappily for me, she can't stay longer.
一個月后  寂靜令她變聾
After a month, she finds the quiet deafening.
菲力叔叔
Uncle Philip. Hello, old boy.
你知否發生了什么事
Uncle Philip, what do you think happened ? Oh.
你知我們有貴客到嗎
You didn't know we had a guest.
你轉過身看看
You turned your back, and see what happens.
我侄女柏茜雅馬田  美臣先生
My niece, Patricia Martin, Mr. Mason.
你好嗎  你好
How do you do ? How do you do ?
叔叔  路上有架車滿載探員
Uncle Philip, there was a car full of detectives down the road.
他們想知道往市中心的路
They wanted to know the way to town.
他們正在找尋一個逃犯
They're searching for a man.
已在電臺全面廣播
It was on all the radios.
他們說那人是個危險的罪犯
A really dangerous criminal--
警方總愛危言聳聽
My dear, the police are always on the alarmist side.
但他們說那人真的很危險
- But they said this man is really dangerous !
他們一定會這樣說
- I'm sure they did.
若他無殺傷力怎顯得警方是英雄
How could they be heroes if he were harmless ?
柏  別再引述警方的說話了
Would you mind not having any further quotations from the police ?
他們的言論是有計謀的
Their remarks are always so expected.
要杜絕批評
They kill conversation.
你可能覺得我侄女很面熟  美臣
You've probably seen the face of my niece before, Mr. Mason.
對  不知在那里見過她
Why, yes. I was wondering where I'd seen--
其實你應該到處都可見到她
As a matter of fact, you've seen her practically everywhere.
我得悉她的服飾地通行全國
I'm told that billboards she adorns would reach across the continent...
我想不到有人會穿她那些服飾
if placed end to end. I can't imagine who's going to place them end to end,
有誰會仿效她的衣著
nor why they should consider it the thing to do.
叔叔一直不喜歡我當模特兒
Uncle Philip never has been enthusiastic over my career as a model.
親戚總是如此的
Relatives are like that.
你倆打算繼續吃  不理我
My, aren't you two mean, going ahead and eating without me !
我很肚餓  可否將碟遞給我
I'm starving. Would you pass me one of those plates, please, Mr. Mason ?
你已看見他的手銬嗎
- Oh ! - What's the matter ? Have you just seen his handcuffs ?
他進來時我已聽到了
I heard them as soon as he came in.
我相信他正是警方要找的那個人
Uncle Philip, he must be the man they're looking for.
對  有可能
Yes, very probably.
你應將他交給警方
But you should have given him to the police !
你恐懼嗎  恐懼令你如此殘忍嗎
Are you frightened, Pat ? Is that what makes you so cruel ?
你必須這樣做  他是個危險人物
But you've got to ! He's a dangerous man.
柏  美臣可能犯事
Oh, Pat, come on, Mr. Mason may be many things,
但他絕非危險人物
but he's certainly not dangerous.
你別忘記身為美國公民的責任
Uncle Philip, it's your duty as an American citizen !
我為身美國公民的責任
It is my duty as a citizen...
是要相信他是無辜的
But you should have given him to the police !
直至他被定罪
to believe a man innocent until he's been proved guilty.
別對我說權責吧
Don't tell me about my duty.
人們會以為我古板守舊
It makes you sound so stuffy.
此外我對公民責任有自己的見解
Besides, I have my own ideas about my duties as a citizen.
有時候需要漠視法律的
They sometimes involve disregarding the law.
你打算怎樣做
But what are you going to do with him ?
你打算怎樣對付他
我打算將他交給你
I'm going to turn him over to you, my dear.
你要送他去找添  那打鐵匠
And you're going to drive him down to Tim, the blacksmith,
將那荒謬的裝置從他手腕拆除
and have those preposterous contraptions removed from his wrists.
菲力叔叔  我怎能做這種事
Oh, how could I do a thing like that ?
你應知道我的目光較你遠大
'Cause you know I can see a great deal farther than you can.
我能預知未來的事  例如  被冤枉
I can see intangible things. For example, innocence.
美臣先生  你愿跟我侄女去嗎
Will you go with my niece, Mr. Mason ? Oh. yes. sir.
愿意  若你不介意的話
Uh, if you don't mind ?
我該怎樣對鐵匠說
What'll I tell the blacksmith ?
告訴他  美臣是我朋友及貴賓
Tell him Mr. Mason is my friend and my guest.
他不會再問你其他問題的
He won't ask any other questions.
去吧  柏
Go ahead, Pat.
跟她去吧  巴利
Go with her, Barry.
巴利是你的名字
Barry, I know, is your name.
但我聽得出美臣并非真姓氏
Your voice explained to me that ''Mason'' isn't.
但正如我跟你說過的
But as I told you before,
名字并不太重要
names are of such little importance.
我不知道如何感激你  馬田先生
I-- I don't know how to thank you, Mr. Martin.
去吧  巴利
Go ahead, Barry. Go ahead.
做些我希望做到的事情吧
And do the things I wish I could do.
祝你好運
Good luck, Barry, and for heaven's sake,
要練習敲擊樂器啊
get back in practice on that triangle !
鐵匠的店鋪很遠嗎
Is the blacksmith's shop very far ?
不太遠  由此直去
Not ver. Right along here.
他真的不會有問題
And, uh, is he-- Is he really all right ?
他跟我叔叔是好朋友
He and my uncle are great friends. Oh.
那么  我看不會有問題了
I guess he's all right, then.
別擔心  他沒問題的
You needn't worry. He's all right.
他是個親切的人
He's a darling blacksmith,
唯一擔心是他應付手銬的經驗
only I'm not sure how much experience he's had with handcuffs.
介意我看看手銬嗎
Do you mind if I see them ?
不知他會如何拆除它
I wonder-- I can't quite see.
我看不清楚  可否拿近一點
Could you hold them nearer ?
現在我可安心點了
Now I feel better.
我看你一定會
I'll bet you do.
我看這樣會令你高興
I'll bet this makes you feel great.
你想知的打鐵匠店在后面兩里
The blacksmith shop is two miles back.
我們正前往警局途中
We're on our way to the police.
你叔叔肯定會以你為榮
Your uncle's gonna be proud of you !
世上很少老人家像我叔叔般仁慈
The world isn't full of kind old gentlemen
你嘗試去找吧  若叔叔多了解你
. You're gonna find that out.
也不會如此仁慈對待你
Even my uncle wouldn't have been so kind if he'd known more.
向前走吧  我做過些什么
All right, go ahead. What'd I do ?
我也想知道
I'd be happy to know.
若你犯的是其他案件
If it had been any other crime--
若因饑餓而偷竊
if a man had stolen because he was starving,
又或者為了自衛而殺人
even committed murder to defend himself,
我也不會將你送交警方
maybe I wouldn't tell the police.
唯一原因是你進行陰謀破壞
But there's only one reason why a man commits sabotage.
這比殺人更差勁
That's worse than murder.
你令我驚訝  我贊同你每句說話
Surprise, Miss Martin. I agree with ever word.
別再跟我說話了
Please don't talk to me.
我喜歡說
That'll be my pleasure.
我看她不喜歡說話
Well ! I'll see that she doesn't !
以后別再這樣開車  很辛苦的
Never try driving this way; it hurts.
我要去截車
I'm stopping the first car I see !
對不起
Help !
對不起  沒有你我寸步難行
Come on. I can't get along without you.
放我走  救命呀  快報警
Let me go ! Help ! Help ! Get the police !
救命呀
Help !
他倆定是一對怨侶
My, they must be terribly in love.
這車可能過熱了
Looks as though this car has been overheated.
是風扇壞了
Fan's broken.
我很冷
I'm cold.
我知道  肚子也餓吧
Yeah, I know. And you're hungry.
主要是冷
Now mostly I'm cold.
若你不再扮英雄  相信我吧
If you'd stop trying to be a hero and decide to be on my side,
或許可替你想辦法驅寒
maybe we could do something about your being cold.
生一堆火
Build a fire ?
不  我沒這打算
No, I wasn't exactly thinking of that.
我不作嘗試并非要侮辱你
Well, I didn't want to insult you by not even trying.
你為何要告發我  你的照片
What do you want to turn me in for ?
已到處可見  仍想搏取知名度
Haven't you got your picture in enough places now ?
我只是盡公民責任
I just want to do my duty.
你是不明白的
That's hard for you to understand.
你為何不信我是無辜的
Why won't you believe I'm all right ?
因你的表現不合情理
You don't make sense.
若沒做過  應去面對警方
If you hadn't done it, you would have gone to the police.
我跟你說過  只是時間問題
It's a question of time !
若去投案將要花數周時間作解釋
It'd take weeks to convince them.
若他們像你般愚昧更要花數月
If they're as dumb as you are, it'll take me months !
你知否我們離開梳打鎮很遠了
Do you think we're very far from Soda City ?
我不知  到了下一個鎮再問路
I don't know. We'll ask at the next town. If there's a next town.
無論如何我也不相信杜賓那件事
Anyway, I don't believe that part about Tobin.
你不相信
You don't believe it
因為他擁有農場  泳池及大屋
because he's got a big ranch and a pool--
任何美國人也不會置信
No. It's just hard to believe that about any American.
但人相信我是兇徒
Well, you believe it about me!
你不同  你像個陰謀破壞者
Well, you're different. You look like a saboteur.
你有破壞的傾向
You have a saboteur's disposition.
難道你決定相信我了
Don't tell me you've decided to be on my side.
不  我很冷
No, I'm cold.
你在浪費寶貴光陰
Say, aren't you wasting your very valuable time,
去欣賞風景
sitting up here admiring the scenery ?
唏  你看
Hey, look at that.
我們有伙伴了
Looks like we've got company.
他們列隊到來做什么呢
What do you suppose all that's doing way up here ?
他們移動很慢
They aren't moving very fast, are they ?
知否我們可怎么辦
You know what we can do ?
噢  你是不會的
Oh, no, you won't.
我不會冒險的
Sorry, I can't take a chance.
到了下一個站定會告發你
You're right. I'll kill you the first opportunity I get.
放開我
Let go of me ! Let me go ! Ouch !
救命啊
Help ! Help !
可否暫時放過我
Won't you give me one break ?
待我們到梳打鎮后再作打算
. Wait 'til we get to Soda City ?
對不起  我要留下你
All right. I'm sorry I've got to leave you here alone,
去做早決定的事
but I told you what I've got to do.
我只有一件事要做
There's only one thing
我警告你  這里有很多蛇
I want to warn you about. Snakes.
當然  只有五六種是有毒的
There are a lot out here. There's only five or six poisonous kinds.
它們是又長又滑的
But there are a lot of long, slippery, slimy ones.
巴利
- Barry!
我可重見天日了  比蛇更自由
- I'm coming up in the world; I'm better than the snakes.
巴利  求求你
Barry, please!
你要跟隨我嗎  是的
Are you with me ? Yes, yes!
什么事令你改變主意了
What made you change your mind ?
因我處身荒野便不能告發你
I can't turn you in if I'm stuck out there.
那么  回去跟蛇蟲鼠蟻為伍吧
So that's it. Go back with the reptiles.
放開我
Let me go !
誰在這里  你們不能在這里
Who's there ? You've got no right here!
快停手  下車
Stop it and get off!
是偷渡客
Now, now, Major. Ah, stowaways.
在沙漠中又再捉多兩個流浪者
In the middle of this desert sea, we acquired two more vagabonds.
像我們一樣  是游牧民族
Bedouins like ourselves,
什么  只不過是兩個小伙子
eh, Esmeralda ? They're just a couple of kids !
我們汽車壞了  徒步走了數里
Uh, our car broke down, and we've walked for miles.
見你的車不想吵醒你
We hopped on. We didn't want to
幫擅自登車
wake you at this hour.
壞車
Broke down, eh ?
我們在公路上未見有壞車
We didn't pass no wrecks on the highway.
你們所說的全是慌話
- Sounds like a pack of lies.
我們是從小路出來的
- We were off on a side road.
在月色下停車  實在美妙
I know. A moonlight night and a parked car. That's nice.
不  真的  我們只不過
- Oh, no, really-- -
艾瑪拉  你總愛想入非非
Esmeralda ! Everywhere you search for sex.
擦干凈你的眼睛抬頭觀星吧
Get your eyes out of the mud and look up at the stars.
對不起  我叫邦斯
Oh, I beg your pardon. My name is Bones.
人稱我為人類骷髏頭你好
I'm also known as the Human Skeleton.
她是艾瑪拉  是長滿胡子的女士
- How do you do ? - And this is Esmeralda, our bearded lady.
她加入我們的隊伍令我們自豪
Naturally, we're very proud to have her as a member of our group.
你們一定疲倦了
You must be tired.
進來坐下  休息一會
Come on in and rest.
我們要到一處叫梳打鎮的地方
We're trying to get to Soda City,
我看是在北面兩百里
a couple hundred miles north, I think.
大概天明便到達  休息一會兒吧
You won't get there 'til morning, so make yourselves comfortable.
我來介紹另一伙伴泰坦妮
You must meet our other coworker:
她是個龐然大物
Titania, our little human mountain.
是一座人肉山你好
A very great lady, indeed.
這里發生什么事了
How do you do ? What's goes on there ?
我們吵醒你們嗎
Oh, did we wake you ?
我已醒了
Oh. I was awake.
你想辦法替米露妮解決失眠癥吧
I wish you'd tell Minnie to do something about that insomnia.
她令我整晚輾轉反側
I've been tossing and turning.
你叫瑪莉高掩蓋那丑陋的面孔吧
Tell Marigold to shut her silly old face.
你們兩個別再互相挖苦吧
Are you girls not speaking to each other again ?
瑪莉高恨我
Marigold's mad
因為我的艷光掩蓋她的
because I got her beau away from her.
告訴米露妮  我聽到些閑言
Kindly tell Minnie I heard that last remark.
我才不稀罕那個所謂俊男
I wouldn't have the gentleman as a gift.
他只不過是個貪新鮮的男人
A common novelty seeker !
女孩子  別失禮我們的貴賓
Girls ! What will our guests think ?
他很可愛啊
Hey, he's cute !
聽到嗎  她又來了
You hear that ? There she goes again.
別再爭吵了
Stop your squabbling.
他們經過長途跋涉  已很疲倦
They're tired.- They've been walking for miles!
沒有人讓你們搭順風車嗎
- Nobody gave you a lift.
我明白了
I know
一般人都是鐵石心腸的
The normal are normally coldhearted.
別再廢話  趕他們下車
Get these tramps off !
鐵石心腸
A cold heart.
你怪我也要這樣做  趕他們下車
I won't take no insults. Get 'em off.
美捷  別哄我了
Aw, Major, honey-- Don't ''honey'' me !
我有合約在身  要安全運送
I've got a contract. It provides for safe transportation
合約沒要求我接載無業游民
and don't say nothing about hobos !
是警察
That's the police.
他們一定是在尋人
They must be looking for somebody.
他們要找什么人呢
Who could they want ?
我猜是找我
Me, I guess.
一個戴上手銬逍遙法外的年青人
Oh ! They came for you.
他們為何要追捕你
He has handcuffs on. What do they want you for ?
是因為一宗別人犯的案
For something somebody else did.
我不相信他會犯案
I don't believe he's done anything wrong !
我隨時愿意舍命幫他
I'll go to bat for him anytime.
我常說
I've always told
米露妮遲早會惹官非
Minnie she'd get mixed up with the police if she wasn't careful.
他們從前面開始搜查了
They're starting to search at the front.
你在等什么  將他交給警方吧
Well, what are you waiting for ? Hand them over to the police.
他絕對正確
He's perfectly right.
他是個麻煩的人
He's a little stinker.
這似乎是很為難的事
Seems terrible,
但我們留住了  我們便會很為難
but it would be terrible, too, if we got into trouble.
邦斯  通知警方
Bones, call the cops !
且慢  美捷
Just a minute, Major.
我們采取這方法來解決這窘境吧
In this situation I find a parallel for the present world predicament.
我們現在形勢不利
We stand defeated at the outset.
艾瑪拉富有同情心  但卻消極
You, Esmeralda, have sympathy, yet you're willing
任由事情發生
to remain passive.
我有個想法  我將不理會警方
I have a belief, and yet I'm tempted to let myself be overridden by force.
除了那罪無可赦的小子外
The rest of you, with the exception of this malignant jerk,
其他人全是無辜的  被人瞞騙
are ignorant of the facts and, therefore, confused.
我們是奉行民主的人
Thank heaven we're still members of a democracy.
來投票作決定吧
We'll vote.
不準投票  我反對投票
- I'm against voting!
法西斯主義者
- Fascist !
結果顯而易見的
You know how we stand so far.
那對孿生姐妹互相對立
The twins, as usual, are on opposite sides.
正反票各一
And so their votes pair.
泰坦妮猶豫未決  是中立票
Titania's on both sides at once and, therefore, neutral.
美捷贊成交警方
The major is for delivering these people to the police,
我則反對
and I, frankly, am against it.
艾瑪拉  由你作決定了
Esmeralda, the decision is up to you.
我不想任何人有麻煩
I don't want any trouble any more than anybody else,
當你們討論時  我發現了一件事
but while you've been talking, I've been looking at something--
一個很甜蜜的場面
something pretty fine too.
我看見那位小女孩
I've been looking at that little girl
她一直靠在他的身旁
standin' beside that poor man.
不發一言  絕不懷疑他
Never a word. Never a question.
接受他所做的一切
Takin'everything he's had to take,
無論發生任何事也支持他
stringin'along with him.
大難臨頭仍支持著
And I've been thinking, it's the good people
她一定是好人
that stick when anybody's in trouble,
世上已沒有太多好人了
and there aren't many good people in the world.
相信大家會小數服從多數
I think that we, all of us, know that better than most.
這絕非等閑之事
It isn't something you see every day of the week.
因此我投票
- So I vote--
你做得好  你不離棄他們
- We don't give them up. Good girl, Esmeralda !
這是顛覆行為  我不贊成
This is subversive ! I won't stand for it !
你不可以這樣  要服從多數人
Oh, no, you don't ! You'll abide by the will of the majority.
我們回到原位  假裝熟睡
Back in your places and pretend to be asleep.
就此決定  你坐在這里
That's all you have to do.
年青人  你要躲起來
Here, you sit here. Come on, young man. We've got to hide you.
關掉所有燈  換上這套衣服
Turn all the lights off. Here. Take off your coat and put this on.
全部人起床
Come on. Wake up in there !
什么事  萬圣節
Hey, what is this ? Halloween ?
是警察
Police.
真的嗎
Is that so ? Haven't you got anything better to do...
為何在深夜吵醒守法的人
than waking up law-abiding citizens in the middle of the night ?
我們要找一個男人及他的女同黨
We're lookin'for a man and his woman companion.
他是黑發的
He's got dark hair,
年齡約二十至二十五歲
between the ages of 20 and 25.
那女士挺漂亮的  有見過他們嗎
The dame's supposed to be good-lookin'. Have you seen him ?
如此普通的人隨處可見
Now, where would I see anybody as normal as that ?
她是誰  不像你的馬戲團員
Who's this ? Doesn't look like one of your troupe.
她是團員之一
Sure, she's one of us.
是蛇舞女郎
She's our little snake charmer.
她坐著的是一箱蛇  在安撫它們
Right now, she's sitting on a box of snakes so they don't get lonesome.
想不到如此美女竟與蛇為伍
Can you imagine that ? A good-lookin'gal too.
你們可以回去睡覺了
Well, I guess you can all go back to sleep now.
蛇舞女郎  別把婦女看扁啊
A snake charmer! Well, well. You never can tell about women.
沒事了  你可出來了
It's all right. You can come out now.
等等  執法人員  回來
Wait,Justice, come back !
坐下  我們已經啟程了
Sit down here ! We're on our way.
不知該如何感激你
I don't know how I can thank you, sir.
沒事了
It's all right. my boy.
助人為快樂之本
Gives you a good feeling when you can help somebody.
你們有權知道事件的始末
You've got a right to know what this is about. It's all right.
你的女友也信你  我們也會信你
If that little girl can trust you, I guess we can.
寶貝  你受盡委屈了
The baby ! She's had a tough time.
可憐的女孩  已筋疲力竭了
Poor little girl. She's worn out.
我來照顧她
I'll take care of her.
來吧  我們走
Come on. Let's go.
讓那些蛇安睡吧
Better let the snakes get some sleep.
它們明天會精神奕奕了
They have to look good tomorrow.
對不起
I'm sorry.
為什么
What for ?
因為我那么笨拙
For being such a dope. I was scared.
你不驚慌才算是笨蛋
You'd have been a dope if you hadn't been scared.
你已太疲累了
You're tired; that's all that's the matter with you.
睡一會兒便沒事了
Get some sleep. You'll be fine.
我會睡的
I can go to sleep, all right.
我很疲倦了
I'm so tired.
有件事想告訴你
I want to tell you something.
我相信你
I believe you.
真的嗎  柏茜亞
Do you, Pat ?
你以前是不信的
You didn't, you know.
這是自由的國家  可改變主意嗎
It's a free country. A girl can change her mind, can't she ?
當然可以
Sure, she can.
謝謝你
Thank you, Pat.
他們令我感到羞愧
They made me so ashamed.
他們很好人  信任別人
They're so nice and trusting.
他們確實了不起
They're wonderful people,
所有人  除了那討厭的美捷
all except that nasty little major and that...
還有那小氣的孿生妹妹
mean twin.
你不應怪責那個胖婦
I don't suppose you can really blame the fat lady, though,
尤其是當她變成這般身材后
when a woman has lost her figure that way.
"梳打鎮"
歡迎光臨梳打鎮
Welcome to Soda City.
是蘊藏梳打的心臟地帶
The heart of the bicarbonate belt.
我們到鎮內逛逛吧
Well, we might as well do the town.
里面什么也沒有
There's nothing here. Come on.
看來我們遲來一步了
I suppose we are a little late.
對不起  早知道便不帶你來
Sorry, darling. I knew I shouldn't have brought you here.
我并非向你投訴
I'm not complaining.
現在好極了  是嗎
This is great, isn't it ?
已解決我的所有問題
The solution to all my problems.
我要倚賴這地方了
I was counting on this place.
這荒蕪之地距離五千里
A dump like this, 5,000 miles from nowhere.
你看  仍有人住的
Look at this. It's been in use.
我們到窗前
Let's go around to the window.
小心割傷手
Careful! Don't cut yourself.
喂  掛線了
Hello ? Hello ?
這是什么類型的電話
Hung up. What sort of phone is that ?
是戰地電話
It's a field telephone.
這房間有美麗景觀
Well, a room with a view.
為何要開這個洞
What do you suppose they cut that for ?
我不知道
I don't know.
看
Say, look.
有個?腳架
Tripod.
高度吻合
Looks like it's the right height.
一定有東西連接的
Yeah. Something else goes with this.
在這里
There !
對了
That's it.
看見什么嗎
See anything ?
還沒有
Not yet.
讓我看
Let me see !
那是
Why, that's a-- Why, Barry ! Yeah.
我們拿走它  接住
Better put this away. Take that.
你看什么
- Say ! The wood.
那些木條那又如何
- What about it ?
他們不會在爐上燃燒木材
You wouldn't burn that.
為何不會
Why not ?
產生的煙被人發覺
The smoke would show.
是汽車聲
That's a car.
你躲起來
You better hide.
不  進來
No, not here.
唏  你在這里干什么
Hey. What d'you think you're doin' around here ?
你好嗎  你何時回來的
I, uh-- I was wonderin' when you'd get here. Where you from ?
你來自何方  在這里干什么
What are you stickin' around here for?
對不起
Excuse me.
"巴利堅尼涉嫌破壞兵工廠"
我不明你如何會知道這地方
Funny, you knowin' about this place. I don't quite get it.
你要考慮清楚
You might have thought it over more carefully.
你到來對我們毫無幫助
Your coming here doesn't help us a bit.
他被通緝  竟在此出現
The heat's on this guy,
是杜賓派我來的
and he shows up here.
那老頭子定是傻了  竟派他來
Tobin sent me. The old man must be off his nut sending him up here.
尼爾信  你說話要小心
Be a little more careful, Neilson.
你竟然在人前批評他
Your criticisms in front of other people.
對  別用這口吻批評老頭子
- Yeah. Don't talk that way about the old guy.
我會小心言行的
- I'll watch out for myself.
我也是  別忽略我  杜賓叫我來
Me too. Don't forget about me. That's why Tobin sent me here.
他說你會懂得如何照顧我
He said you'd know how to take care of me.
尼爾信  形勢已很明顯
I guess that makes it pretty clear, Neilson.
我不知  突然有個人來到沙漠
I don't know. A guy walks in, and right away I get orders.
要我接受命令  我實在不太明
It ain't so clear to me.
你看到報導便不視我為陌生人
I'm a little better than a stranger, if you'll remember my clippings !
對  堅尼在南部干了驚天大事
Yes. Mister, uh, Kane has done pretty well down south.
我們不應漠視他的成就
His accomplishments can't be disregarded. At least I hope not.
他的表現起碼也值得我們認同
A man that has served as well as he has is entitled to recognition.
不單如此  更應受到保護
More than that-- protection.
你們要照顧我
You guys have got to take care of me.
我肯定公司會盡力而為
The firm will do its best.
公司是出名厚待雇員的
They're quite loyal to their employees.
尼爾信翻查公司紀錄便了解一切
Neilson will see that the firm's record is maintained.
你說來容易  你安坐東岸
You got it easy, you guys from back East.
發號施令  一貫如此
You give orders. You do that, all right.
大人物只做文書工作
The big boys with the desk jobs.
你只需坐在辦公椅上打電話
All you gotta do is reach for a telephone, sit back,
而外面的人卻要背上黑鍋
and us guys out here have gotta take the rap.
看來  我也想回去工作了
I think I'll go back East for a while.
你對公司毫不忠心
You're not a very good example of loyalty.
因為我已有點厭倦
Yeah ? Well, I'm gettin' just a little bit tired. See ?
我也是  我厭倦了聽這些說話
So am I ! Let's get goin' !
我徒步而來
The trip here was no pushover.
長途跋涉絕不輕松
I had to hoof it most of the way.
我沒地方讓你藏匿并非由我負責
I got no place to hide you out. That ain't my line.
并非由你負責
That ain't your line, huh ?
你呢  你似乎也沒興趣管
What about you ? You don't seem so interested either !
你是公司的主腦
I suppose you're just the big brains !
你已得償所愿  在暗暗偷笑
Or maybe you take a chance just for laughs !
我舍命相從
Maybe it doesn't work that way.
落得如此田地
Maybe I'm the only guy that sticks his neck out !
我做了一件驚天動地的大事
Well, get this ! I pulled a big job,
被警方追輯
and they're after me !
你要照顧我否則你倆也會被拘捕
And you guys have gotta take care of me, or you're gonna have some trouble!
我要離開這地區
I've gotta get out of this part of the country !
這里烈日當空  腳底飽受煎熬
The ground's burning up under my feet !
我要回到東岸
I've gotta get back East !
那里人煙稠密  不易被人發覺
It's more crowded and a guy doesn't stand out, like here !
你別緊張  別沖動
Take it easy. Hang onto your nerve.
我已克制  我已忍受夠了
I've been hanging on long enough !
我明白你的困難
I understand your difficulties,
你對所講過的說話致歉  但是
but in this business...
為了安全
we always have to make sure.
我現在已清楚你的為人
I think I know him now.
我會駕車回東岸  你跟我走
I'm driving back East. You'd better come with me. All right.
好的  我們啟程
Let's get goin'.
執拾一切  別留下痕跡
Get all the things together.
我們走后便不會再回來
After we leave, I want this place cleaned up. You won't be coming back here.
為什么  這地方被監視嗎
Why not ? You think they got the place spotted ?
我要確介安全
I'm making sure.
你另覓地方吧
You'll have to find another place and store all this stuff.
這絕不容易啊
It's not gonna be easy.
這是你的職責  你若不勝任
If you can't handle it,
我會另覓人選
I'll have to get someone else.
好的  我會處理好
All right. I'll handle it.
你需要帶些衣服
You'll need some clothes.
是四十二號  我的手銬怎么辦
Size 42. What'll we do about these ?
你是如何弄斷它的
How did you manage to break them ?
是用汽車風扇
On an automobile fan.
你真聰明
Very bright of you. I think we can even take care of that.
我們會處理的  但現在先起程
But let's get started now.
你聽到嗎  是何處發出的聲音
Did you hear something ?Where does that lead to ?
是另一房間  另一個出口
Just another room. The way out.
我們知道堅尼
We figure that Kane
及其他人正往紐約
and the other fellows are probably headin' for New York.
有什么需要我幫忙嗎
If there's anything I can do.
我們很感激你
We sure appreciate that.
這是任何人也應做的事
Why, anyone would have done the same thing. That's right.
對  但本案卻有分別
This war sure makes a difference.
所有人也想參與本案
Everybody wants to get in and pitch.
你可否將紐約的地址給我
Now, if you'll give me your address in New York, Miss Martin,
你回去后我們可聯絡你
we can contact you back there.
到時可致電告訴我乘哪一班飛機
Or maybe you could wire me which plane you're taking.
我們會盡快去接你
We may want to get ahold of you fast.
我會的  我先回去叔叔的家
I can do that when I get back to my uncle.
好的  馬田小姐  保持聯絡
Okay. Just keep in touch.
這條路雖然要多走幾里
I'm glad we came this way. It adds a few miles,
但我有點傷感
but I've become a little sentimental.
想看它最后一眼
I want to take a last look at it.
美好的風景
Beautiful, isn't it ? A great monument to man's industry...
將被摧毀了
and his stubborn faith in the future.
你們快可前進了
You'll be moving along soon.
有攝影機或槍械嗎
Are you carrying any cameras or firearms at all ?
完全沒有  警官
Nothing at all, Officer. You. sir ?
你呢  沒有
No, sir.
這水壩定可提供很多能源
They must get a lot of power from this dam.
供應洛杉磯75%的電力
I think it supplies about 7 5% for the Los Angeles district,
當然包括兵工廠的電力
including most of the power for the defense plants.
你跟杜賓很熟嗎
Do you think there's-- Do you know Tobin ver well ?
不  我在他農場見過一面
No. I met him just that once at his ranch.
他的兒子跟他在一起嗎
Did he have the child with him ?
他的孫女  他很喜歡這孫女
His grandchild ? Yes. He seemed to be very fond of her.
對  這是我喜歡老杜賓的原因
Yes. That's one of the things I like about old Tobin:
他深愛那小女孩
his love for that little girl.
證明他有愛心  你知道嗎  我也有孩子
Evidence of a good heart.I have children too, you know ?
我有兩個兒子  分別兩歲和四歲
Oh ? Two boys. Nice little fellows. Aged two and four.
四歲那個很頑皮  一定是有毛病
The four-year-old is naughty at times.He's quite a problem.
買件玩具給他  半小時后便搞壞
We get him a new toy and within half an hour it's smashed to bits.
之后
And then, sometimes, after it's all over,
他卻會后悔
he seems almost sorry.
有時候我希望幼子是個女兒
Sometimes I wish my younger child had been a girl.
我妻常為我的怪習慣而爭執
In fact, my wife and I argue over a little idiosyncrasy I have.
我想待幼子年紀稍大才剪發
I don't want his hair cut short until he's much older.
你認為這樣對他有壞處嗎
Do you think it'd be bad for him ?
我不知  有可能吧
It might be.
我幼時長得一頭金色曲發
When I was a child, I had long golden curls.
人們常在街上停步來贊賞我
People used to stop to admire me.
時移勢易  替他剪發可免生意外
Things are different nowadays. A haircut might save him a lot of grief.
我們開車了
Ah, we're on our way.
當月色
We love
在夜空照耀時
While the moon
我們觸摸繁星  愛是屬于我們的
We touch the stars Love is ours
晚風在夜空
Like winds that sigh
發出呼嘯聲
Embrace the sky
今晚我們
Tonight we love
愛上了月色
In the glow
月色正溫柔地照耀
That blows so softly
別往辦公室  駛往401  是
Drive to 401 instead of the office. Okay.
有問題嗎
Anything wrong ?
很多問題  我剛致電回辦公室
I've just called the office.
但電話線已被截斷
They've disconnected the phone.
仍是那間電話公司  應付了帳的
Same old phone company. Should've paid the bill.
沒時間開玩笑了
This is no time for jokes !
是警方  他們在監視辦公室
The police. They're watching the office.
截斷電話是給我們的暗示
The phone is our signal.
他們是否要監視我
Think they're watching for me ?
我不知  誰會知你在紐約呢
I don't know. Who'd know you were in New York ?
對  你說得對
Yeah. I guess you're right.
明天要見布連  要我開車嗎
How about Brooklyn tomorrow ? Do you want me on the job ?
你何時才學懂閉嘴
When are you gonna learn to keep your mouth shut ?
對不起  我以為他有份參與
Sorry. I-I thought he was in on it.
閉嘴
Shut up.
沒問題  我擅于保守秘密
It's all right. I'm good at keeping secrets.
我們走
Let's go.
費文先生
Mr. Freeman.
你好嗎  費文先生
Hi, Mr. Freeman. Hello.
高興見到你  旅途愉快嗎
Ah, pleased to see you. Have a good trip ?
很好  謝謝你  羅拔
Yes. Thank you, Robert.
太太在樓上  她很憂心地等著你
Madam is upstairs. She's waiting anxiously.
謝謝  我們到樓上  這邊走
Oh, thank you, Robert. We'll go right up. This way.
他是誰
Who was that ?
這是酒店  有什么慶典
Hey, is this a hotel ? What's the festivity ?
這是富商的活動
It's for a very worthy cause.
瑟頓太太常借出地方辦慈善活動
Mrs. Sutton often gives her house over to charity affairs.
她是個慷慨的女人  但我恐怕
She's a very generous woman, but
她會不喜歡見到我們如此衣著
she isn't going to be pleased to see us.
你們這班低效率的笨蛋
Idiots, all of you. Stupid, inefficient idiots.
所有事也要我處理
Everything is left to me.
要我東奔西跑
I have to hover over you like an old hen.
對不起  瑟頓太太
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sutton.
樓下的賓客正等待我露面
The guests expect me to put in an appearance.
他們付出二十五元要討回代價
As you say, they want something for their $ 25!
我不想樂善好施的聲譽受損
I will not have my benevolence abused.
我的名譽地位是很重要的
My life, my position-- they're important to me.
我會盡力而為  瑟頓太太
I'll do my best.
希望你的能力會改善
I wish your best were a little better.
費文先生  很高興此刻遇到你
Oh. Mr. Freeman. I'm glad you've come at this time.
我剛剛對愛德華說  這年青人
I was just telling Edward-- Is this the young man ?
我不能讓他在此作避難所
Must you bring him here ? I certainly can't furnish him with sanctuary.
這屋里全是貴賓  顯赫人物
This house is full of guests, important people !
你明白我的處境嗎  這年青人在此
Don't you understand ?
警方已監視人的辦公室
The police are already watching your office.
祈求他們不會到來
Thank goodness they'll never come here.
你的愚蠢行為
But a little more of your stupid behavior,
我這尊貴的大屋也難以庇護你啊
and even the respectability of my house won't shield you.
對不起  我是不會無故登門的
I'm sorry. We can't leave any loose ends.
好了  別再隱瞞陰謀了
All right ! But for heaven's sake,
告訴我那女孩的事
stop playing the conspirator.
你可問他
Now tell me all you know about the girl, or ask him.
你為何不告訴你關于那女孩的事
Why didn't you tell me about the young lady back in Soda City ?
我以為不重要
Well, I didn't think it was important.
她只是個普通女孩
She was just a girl.
她攔載我  她漂亮
She picked me up. She was pretty.
或許是冒險
I guess it was kind of risky. Well, there you are.
對不起  我令你冒風險
I'm so sorry to have exposed you to any risk.
她來這里干什么
What's she doing here ?
你再遇我  覺得詫異嗎
You're surprised to see me again.
你是如何進來的
How did you get here ?
她如何進來并不重要
It doesn't matter.
問題是你沒理由帶她來
There was no reason to bring her at all!
我在油站打電話時才知此事
You see, I just learned on the telephone at the gas station...
她最失策是在梳打鎮讓你下車后
that she was most indiscreet after she left you at Soda City.
便直接前往找當地的警長
She went to the sheriff, who,
幸好警長是我的好朋友
fortunately, happened to be a good friend of ours.
別浪費時間解釋了
Don't waste time in explanations.
你快將那女孩帶離本屋  全部人
You've got to get the girl out of this house.
我不想聲譽受損
I will not have my benevolence abused!
你自作聰明  變成幫了大忙
So you played smart. That's great. That's a big help to all of us.
不  我絕不聰明
No, I wasn't smart at all.
我四天以來絕不聰明
I haven't been smart for four days.
我在警長面前也有點猶豫
Even when I went to the sheriff, I hesitated.
我討厭做些令你惹麻煩的事
I hated to do anything that might get you into trouble.
我同情你  真后悔不將你留下
Yeah, I sympathize. The mistake I made was
讓你與蛇為伍
not leaving you with the snakes !
起碼可學會響尾蛇的聲音
You might have learned to rattle.
我當初沒看錯你
I was right about you.
堅尼先生  晚上好
Good evening, Mr. Kane.
想不到你竟是書呆子
I didn't know you were a bookworm.
讓我選些適合你的東西送給你
You must let me choose something appropriate for you.
一些你不會太難去理解的
Something not too difficult.
讓我看
Let me see.
"身份不詳的死者"
有了  這是經典之作
Here we are. This'll do admirably.
是一些預言
Remarkable work. Somehow prophetic.
查理  你到來做什么  一派胡言
Why are you here, Charles ? What's all this nonsense about books ?
我是個難民
I am a refugee.
終于加入這令人惡心的漂泊隊伍
I have at last joined that revolting group of world travelers.
做一些令人鄙視的事情
One ultimately turns into the thing one despises most.
我應多謝誰  是你  費文先生
And whom have I to thank for it ? You, Mr. Freeman.
我讓那女孩無拘無束地逃走
The girl was allowed to escape unobserved.
她離開堅尼后便去找她的叔叔
She left Mr. Kane, went straight to her uncle.
那可愛的老人家去找警察
That charming old man went to the police.
結果  大班警察來到我家
As a result, a whole hoard of officers came to my house.
僥幸地  他們到來時我并不在家
Luckily, I was leaving when they arrived.
這里的人很忠心
And the others-- the very loyal ones--
他們的忠誠終于獲得回報
Well, they're paying for their loyalty.
真駭人  對不起  查理
How appalling !Your charming house. I'm so sorry, Charles.
實在幸運  你本應更感遺憾
Rather lucky. You might have been sorrier.
費文  你做事更有效率
And you might have been more efficient, Mr. Freeman.
你侮辱我  對你有什么好處
What good is it to insult me ?
我們現在已惹上麻煩
We're in trouble now.
最重要的是確保大家的安全
So the most important thing is to make sure of everyone around us.
確保堅尼安全
Mr. Kane. I'm just not sure.
我想知道他是否安全
I want to know that he's all right.
好一句輕描淡寫  他不只如此
All right ? What an understatement. He's much more than that!
他高貴  溫文純潔
He's noble and fine and pure.
他因此要在這世上得到懲罰
So he pays the penalty that the noble must pay in this world:
各位對他判斷錯誤了
he's misjudged by everyone.
甚至警方也對他誤會了
Why, even the police have a completely erroneous impression of him.
我肯定他是判若兩人
I can assure you that, contrary to what is supposed,
讓他親口對你們說吧
and to what he may have told you,
這年青人絕非自己國家的敵人
that young man is certainly not one of his country's enemies.
查理  你在開玩笑
Charles, you'rejoking!
我說的是千真萬確的
I mean exactly what I say.
堅尼絕對不是我們組織的人
Mr. Kane is definitely no part of our little organization.
你這個仗權勢的人
Your protege. Well, you've done splendidly.
竟然帶他來
You bring him here, you idiot !
我們應如何處置他
What in heaven's name are we going to do with him ?
很好的問題
That's a very appropriate question.
其實沒有太多方法去處置他
Not much we can do with him.
當初將他送交警方  已是大錯
I made the mistake once of turning him over to the police.
在這時刻更加沒可能
That's even more impossible at the moment.
恐怕只有唯一的方法了
I'm afraid there's only one thing we can do.
新法例下  我們全部會被判死刑
You see, the new law threatens all...
我們要用落伍的
So I'm afraid we'll have to apply the ancient axiom:
以牙還牙方法
a tooth for a tooth.
以堅尼還杜賓
A Kane for a Tobin.
別在這里討論這些事情吧
Please don't discuss things of that sort here.
這令人討厭  這地方亦不適宜
It's rather nauseating and out of place.
查理  我很害怕
Oh, Charles, I'm frightened.
我們必須采取預防措施
We must take all precaution.
當然  但也要繼續我們的工作
Of course. We must also continue with our work.
現在太冒險了  已取消炸堤壩
It's too risky now. We're abandoning the dam.
要暫時保持低調
We must remain inactive.
低調  你絕對錯了
Inactive ? You are utterly mistaken.
若如此  我們的組織將告完蛋
Once we do that, our organization is finished.
不惜代價  也要繼續
- We must carry on.
明天那件事如何
- What about tomorrow's work ?
你已準備就緒  不應放棄
Tomorrow's work ? You can't abandon that. But the risk !
但風險  很大  我知道
Is great. I know that.
很可惜  我們要執行命令
Unfortunately, we will have to carry out our orders.
我現在要去加勒比海
I'm leaving for the Caribbean now.
我的處境比你們更差
My position here is more impossible than all of yours.
當然  我很想去中美洲
I'm rather looking forward to Central America.
夏灣拿這季節的天氣很好
Havana will be very gay this season.
我忽然間對這國家厭倦
Somehow I've suddenly had enough of this country.
戰爭令國家頹廢
The war has made it grim.
你就此離開我們而走  逍遙自在
You're leaving us here to face everything, and you'll be on a boat.
要我們面對一切  你去享樂
It all sounds idyllic.
查理  整件事  沒可能的
Oh, Charles. It's-- This whole thing-- It's impossible !
我真的很抱歉
It's panicky. I'm deeply sorr.
噢  你在這里
Ah, there you are!
身為主人家  為何不露面
How unbecoming for a hostess to hide herself away.
對不起  騷擾你們了  我要綁架她
Am I intruding ? I just must kidnap Henrietta.
她遲些會回來
She'll be back.
他們是負責膳食的  有些麻煩
I've had some trouble with these people.
實在很糟糕
They're doing the catering.
我朋友會帶魚子醬來  我可打賭
Our boy will appear any minute with the caviar ! I assure you !
別做傻事  利用內線電話
Don't be a fool! Get to the house phone.
你是如何進來的
How'd you get here ?
我在機場碰到他們
They met me at the airport.
還以為是警員
I thought they were the police.
等等  不能用進來的路線
Wait a minute. No use trying the way I came in.
我們利用正門出去
Let's walk right out through the front door ! Might as well.
我們會留意后門
Yes, sir. We'll watch the back exit.
他們不能出去的
They won't get out.
不妙  對面那人  我進來時見過
No good. See the one on the other side ?
他是同黨  不能走這條路出去
He's one of them. We'll never get out that way.
他們會怎樣對付我們
What can they do ?
他們會捉我們  我們沒有機會
Plenty. They'd grab us. We wouldn't have a chance.
那些人會見到他們對付我們的
These people would see them.
他們會懷疑我倆是擅自闖入的人
If anyone had a question, we're gate crashers.
巴利  這真是一場惡夢
Barry, this is awful.
這里的人
It's like a bad dream. All these people.
有任何一人可信任嗎
Isn't there anyone we can trust ?
當然有  全部人  只是不知哪個
Sure. All of them. Only which one ?
先生  你可能會覺得瘋狂
Excuse me. Uh, this may sound sort of crazy.
不知如何說起  這間屋
I don't even know how to start.
是間諜及陰謀破壞者的溫床
But this whole house is a hotbed of spies and saboteurs.
我可肯定  主人瑟頓太太也是
I'm not being silly. Even our hostess, Mrs. Sutton.
你有問題嗎  你喝醉了嗎
What's the matter with you, sir ? You're drunk.
你連禮服也沒穿
You're not even dressed.
他說什么
What'd he say ?
他以為我喝醉了
He thinks I'm drunk.
我閱報得悉日本人的所為
When I read in the papers what those Japs are doing--
我要去華盛頓找份工作了
Beat it out! Eight to the bar.
我要跳搖擺舞
Yeah, man. Stay in there and pitch.
你付出二十五元入場的嗎
Pardon me. Did you pay $25 to get in here tonight ?
不  我老板給我入場券的
No, not exactly. The boss gave me a ticket. Why ?
我需要你幫忙
I need your help.
你身處一班專欄作家中間
We're among the biggest bunch of fifth columnists in this country.
你開玩笑嗎  是什么鬧劇
Are you kiddin' ? What's the gag ?
我是其中之一
No. I'm on the level.
別開玩笑吧
Aw, you're kiddin'.
他在戲弄我
The guy's tryin' to rib me.
他向你搭訕  齊來搖擺
Aw, sling him your curve. Beat it out. son.
先生  我有些要事跟你談
Excuse me, sir. I'd like to talk to you about something very important.
是什么  堅尼先生  你沒希望了
What is it, Mr. Kane ? You know it's hopeless.
不如到樓上跟杜賓先生共膳吧
Why don't you join Mr. Tobin upstairs in a little supper?
我帶你去
I'll show you the way.
不如停止音樂
Barry, before they get to us,
向各位分開此事
stop the music and tell them ! Tell them all.
這是瑟頓的大宅
This is the Sutton mansion.
我只是個被通緝的小伙子
I'm just a guy from California wanted by the police.
我一開口便會被他們拖下去
They'll grab me as soon as I open my mouth.
我們該怎么辦  難道要坐以待斃
What are you gonna do ? We can't just stand here.
我知道哪里會安全
I know where we'll be safe.
巴利  我很害怕
Barry, I'm scared.
所有人在盡慶  在翩翩起舞
It's so unreal, all these people dancing and having a good time.
對他們提出警告竟當我說笑
And when you try to warn them, they laugh at you.
以為我喝醉了
They think you're drunk.
那個白發老人似乎是個老實人
That man you spoke to seemed like such an honest citizen.
他是這家庭的3朋友
Mmm, just a friend of the family.
整個房間滿布黨羽
The room's well-sprinkled with them.
他們很聰明  令我害怕
They're so smart. That's what frightens me.
他們很聰明  因此冷酷無情
Yeah, they're smart, because they're ruthless.
當你將規條拋諸腦后便很易獲勝
It's easy to win when you forget about the rules.
一個叫富禮的人在加州掉了錢包
A man named Fry drops a wallet in California,
竟導致我倆身陷窘境
and we wind up here, you and me.
唯一好處是可跟你在一起
That's the only good part: I'm with you.
但愿是在別處  在此極也不介意
I wish it were somewhere else. The North Pole. I wouldn't care.
可在冰川上找尋富禮
We might wind up there too, chasing Fry over a glacier !
他太渺少了  我已忘記他了
Fry. He seems so small now. I'd forgotten about him.
我也是
So had I.
我們不能在此一直跳舞
We can't just go on dancing like it's Saturday night at the Palladium.
不能等他們來捉我們
We can't just wait 'til they get us.
你看他們實際會怎樣做
What do you think they'll really do ?
可能正在跟暗殺公司討價還價
They're probably haggling over the price with Murder, Incorporated.
巴昨  求求你
Oh, Barry, please !
對不起  柏
Sorry.
我現在不想走了  還有很多事做
I hate to be out of it. There's still so much to do.
最重要是保住性命  他們說過
If staying alive was ever important. You heard what they said.
明天要去布連執行任務
Something about a job tomorrow in Brooklyn.
是海軍基地  我們其中一人逃走
The navy yard. One of us has got to get out of here.
由我鬧事  你借機逃走
Maybe if I start something, you can make a break for it.
你怎辦
What about you ?
別擔心我  你要搏一次了
You can't worry about me. We've gotta take a chance.
巴利  我倆為何不在一百年前
Oh, Barry, why couldn't I have met you a hundred years ago ?
在海灘相逢
On a beach somewhere.
一百年前的泳衣很羞
Bathing suits looked awfully funny a hundred years ago.
但你穿起來卻會很漂亮
I'll bet you'd look beautiful, though.
我們的行為太放肆了
Afraid we're not behaving very well.
那又如何
What's the difference ?
反正我們不是被邀請到來的
We weren't invited anyway.
柏  這一刻是屬于我的
Pat, this moment belongs to me.
無論如何他們也不能搶走你
No matter what happens, they can never take it away from me.
對不起  你介意嗎
Oh, pardon me. Do you mind?
對不起  你愿意跳舞嗎
Oh, excuse me. Would you, uh-- Would you care to dance ?
當然
Why, yes. Certainly.
你是個更好的舞伴
Oh, you're really a much better dancer.
謝謝  跟你共舞的男子是什么人
Thanks. Who was the man you were dancing with ?
我不知  從未見過他
I have no idea. I never saw him before.
我是指剛才離開你的人
No, I mean the man that just left you.
我知道  講的正是他
I know.
我這一生從未見過他
I never saw him before in my life.
真可惜  希望有機會會再共舞
Oh, what a pity. That was lovely. I hope you will ask me again.
好的  謝謝
Oh, thanks. Thanks a lot.
年青人
Well, young man, you seem to be enjoying yourself.
你很享受這舞會嗎
Charming party, isn't it ?
她在哪里
Where is she ?
你的年輕女士  你不是照顧她嗎
Your young lady ? I thought you were taking care of her.
可能因為頭痛  去了休息
Perhaps she has a headache and is lying down somewhere.
可否跟我一起去找她
Would you like to come with me and look for her ?
讓我來
Hold on.
各位先生女士們
Ladies and gentlemen. Ladies and gentlemen !
請注意
Your attention, please.
我有事要告訴各位
I-I have something to tell you.
是關于這屋和舞會的主人
Something you ought to know about this house and about your hostess.
你繼續講之前
Sir, before you go on,
最好先看看平臺的窗簾
take a look at the curtain on the balcony.
各位  我并不擅于公開演講
I'm, uh, not much of a public speaker,
部份人會奇怪
ladies and gentlemen, and, uh, some of you are probably wondering
我怎會告訴各位
how I can tell you anything about your hostess...
一些大家也不知的女主人事跡
that you, uh, you don't already know--
她的大方有禮
her graciousness,
她的仁慈心  她的樂善好施
her kindness, her many charities.
我要帶給
Well, I want to tell you
各位一個驚喜
that you have a big surprise coming, ladies and gentlemen.
為了今晚的善舉
Tonight, in this house, for the benefit of this great cause...
她已付出很多
for which she's already done so much,
今晚我們的主人瑟頓太太
our hostess, Mrs. Sutton,
打算將珍藏的珠寶送出來拍賣
is putting up for auction...
是著名的瑟頓珠寶其中之一
one of her most treasured possessions, one of the famous Sutton jewels.
瑟頓太太  請移玉步上前
Mrs. Sutton, would you kindly step forward ?
謝謝
- Thank you.
堅尼先生  有位年青女士要找你
- Mr. Kane, the young lady is asking to see you.
真的嗎
Are you sure ?
若我是你  便不會要她久候
I wouldn't keep her waiting if I were you, sir.
好的
Yes.
有誰來幫我
Uh-- Will someone please, uh, uh--
海軍司令  可否上來代替我
W Admiral ?ould you take over for me, please ? I'm wanted on the phone.
我樂意代勞謝謝
Delighted, sir. Thank you.
各位
Ladies and gentlemen,
我會為大家拍賣這手鐲
I will entertain your bids for this beautiful bracelet...
是由我們的主人瑟頓太太送出的
which has been donated by our hostess, Mrs. Sutton.
叫價多少
What am I bid?
一千元
One thousand dollars.
有人出價一千  有更多嗎
One thousand dollars has been bid. Do I have any more ?
一千五百
Fifteen hundred.
已出價一千五百  還有嗎
Fifteen hundred dollars.
一千七百五十
1 ,7 50.
$ 1.7 50.
二千
Two thousand.
有人出價二千元買這美麗的手鐲
她在哪里
Where is she ?
你似乎在尋找那位年輕女士
You seem to have a soft spot for that young lady.
你是受不起這刺激的
You can't afford to make yourself that vulnerable,
何況是要救國
not when you're out trying to save your country.
為何每次提及國家你總嗤之以鼻
You sneer every time you refer to this country.
我不明白  你在這里活得很好
You've done well here. I don't get it.
你不會明的  你是擁護美國的人
No, you wouldn't. You're one
有數以百萬計的人像你一般
of the ardent believers, a good American.
人民默默耕耘  不會提出疑問
Millions like you plod along without asking questions.
我不想用愚蠢來形容
I hate to use the word stupid,
但別無選擇
but it seems to be the one that applies.
數以百萬計的傻瓜
The great masses,
很少人像我般聰明
the moron millions.
他們盲目附和
Well, there are a few of us who are unwilling to just troop along;
很少人像我般聰明  力求上進
a few who are clever enough to see that there's much more to be done...
不輕易自滿
than just live small, complacent lives;
很少美國人要求政府爭取盈余
a few of us who desire a more profitable type of government.
堅尼  你試想想
When you think about it, Mr. Kane,
極權國家的能力尤勝于我們
the competence of totalitarian nations is much higher than ours.
他們能完成既定的任務
They get things done.
對  他們能完成任務
Yeah. They get things done.
炸城市  炸沉船只  嚴刑迫供
They bomb cities, sink ships, torture and murder...
暗殺等任務  你們可從中得利
so you can eat off a gold plate;
這是偉大的哲學
it's a great philosophy.
我并非要放置炸彈或要炸沉船只
I neither intend to be bombed nor sunk, Mr. Kane.
我現在在離開的原因
That's why I'm leaving now.
是因為一切未如我所愿
And if things don't go right for you--
若我們可獲勝  我便會回來
If, uh, we should win--
我希望得到的  是權力
then I'll come back. Perhaps I can get what I want then: power.
正如你渴求安居樂業般
Yes. I want that as much as you want your comfort or your job...
我們的品味有異
or that girl. We all have different tastes, as you can see.
我要用必須的武力來掙回品味
Only I'm willing to back my tastes with the necessary force.
你說來輕描淡寫  這是詭計
You certainly make it sound smooth and easy. That's a trick.
我知你所說的權力會帶來的后果
I know the results of that power you believe in.
它會奪去我朋友及千萬人的性命
It killed my friend, and it's killing thousands like him.
這正是你的目的
That's what you're aiming at.
我知你對這一切絕不感受懊悔
But it doesn't bother you, I can see that.
因為你憎恨所有人
Because you really hate all people.
讓我告訴你
Let me tell you something.
過去四五天我學懂了很多東西
The last four or five days I've learned a lot.
我遇到很多像你這般的人
I've met guys like you, and I've met others--
他們有能力  渴望做些正確的事
people that are helpful and eager to do the right thing,
他們互相幫忙  合力擊退壞人
people that get a kick out of helping each other fight the bad guys.
愛與恨
Love and hate.
世人選擇正途  我也懂作出抉擇
The world's choosing up sides. I know who I'm with.
很多人支持我  是來自世界各地
There are a lot of people on my side-- millions in every country.
我們絕不懦弱  我們很堅強
And we're not soft; we're plenty strong.
憑著赤手空拳  定會獲勝
And we'll fight standing up on
無論你們做什么  我們必勝
our two feet, and we'll win !
從這一刻開始
Remember that, Mr. Tobin. We'll win, no matter what you guys do.
勝利將屬于我們
We'll win if it takes from now until the cows come home !
我們對人權的討論已夠了
Mr. Kane, I think we've discussed the rights of man sufficiently.
我已感到疲倦  相信你也疲倦了
I'm feeling a little tired. You must be too.
羅拔
Robert,
替堅尼安排睡覺的地方
do you think you can arrange for Mr. Kane to sleep somewhere tonight ?
遵命
Yes, sir. Certainly, sir.
夠了  羅拔
That's enough, Robert.
很好
Ver good. sir.
你可獨力看管他嗎  可以
Think you can take care of this ? Yes. sir.
沒有其他事吧  對  謝謝
Will that be all, sir ? Yes. thank you.
無論我們作任何安排或遇到麻煩
It doesn't matter what arrangements we've made, to what trouble we've gone.
整件事最重要的一點是時間性
This whole job hangs on one thing: timing.
若船在戰艦下水前升高
If the slipway goes up
我們將會白費功夫
before the actual launching,
若太遲引爆
then all our efforts have been wasted.
只會引起群眾恐慌
If you blow her too late, then you just scare the crowd.
時間性
Timing, timing, timing.
要在戰艦開始滑行時按擎
That button must not be pressed until the ship starts to move.
我們如何安排逃離現場
What arrangements have been made for getting out ?
攝影機電線脫勾  貨車便可開動
As soon as the cables are unhooked, this truck goes.
我們已安放在大閘上
We got it fixed at the gate.
誰負責控制船臺附近的攝影機
Who's handling the camera near the slipway ?
是我  昨晚已鋪好接駁的電線
I am.The explosives were laid last night.
我只需將連接攝影機的電線解開
I have to hook them up to the camera.
很可惜
Too bad
要損失一部優質的攝影機
we have to lose a good camera.
好了  看來已一切就緒
Everything seems to be taken care of.
我會在新聞中心等你們  祝好運
I'll be waiting at the newsreel office. Good luck.
他們走了嗎  是
- Have they gone ? - Yes.
她怎么了
How is she ? Okay.
很好  正在吃早餐
She's having her breakfast.
令她肅靜有麻煩嗎
Any trouble keeping her quiet ?
沒有  我跟她有個協議
No. I made a deal with her.
那些封眼有嘴的
You see, she got tired of having
膠布令她疲倦
that adhesive tape over her eyes and mouth.
希望你可盡快解決她
I hope we get rid of her soon.
我答應帶孩子去聽管弦樂團表演
I promised to take my kid sister to the philharmonic.
將鑰匙交給我在這里
Give me the key. There it is.
對不起  昨晚未能讓你留在屋里
I'm sorry we couldn't keep you at the house,
因為瑟頓太太的客房數量有限
but Mrs. Sutton has a limited number of guest rooms,
我看堅尼先生會獲得優先接待
and I suppose Mr. Kane was first in line.
我在哪里
Where am I ?
這是商業秘密
Oh. that's a trade secret.
希望你不會畏高吧
I only hope it isn't too high for you here.
堅尼正身處低層
Mr. Kane's quarters are nearer the ground,
得到悉心照料
but he's being well looked after...
像你一樣  享受精美的早餐
and, like you, is probably enjoying a hearty breakfast.
這是誰人的地方
Whose place is that ?
是瑟頓太太的房子
That's Mrs. Sutton's house.
她是誰
Oh. Who's she ?
是有錢的太太
Some rich dame.
看報章知道她做很多善事
Saw something in the paper about her doing things for charity.
就在這里
Right here somewhere. Here.
明天那件事如何
What about tomorrow's work ?
你已準備就緒  不應放棄
Tomorrow's work ? Can't abandon that.
但風險  很大  我知道
But, Charles, the risk-- Is great! I know that.
很可惜  我們要執行命令
Unfortunately, we will have to carry out our orders.
現在幾點了
- What's the time ? - 1 0:50.
10點15分謝謝
Thanks.
布連海軍基地  快
Brooklyn Navy Yard, quick !
有危險
快召警方
看有燈的地方
多少錢  十五仙
How much ? Fifteen.
有找贖嗎  有
Got change ? Yes.
承蒙海軍部門的允許
Courtesy of the Navy Department,
我們得以帶大家到布連海軍基地
we take you to the navy yard,
我們在此作全國聯播
where we will endeavor
為大家報導下水禮
to bring you a description...
是海軍的主力艦阿拉斯加號
of the launching ceremony of the U.S.S. Alaska.
不浪費時間了
And so we switch you now
立即帶大家到現場
to the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
我們現正身處布連海軍基地
Here we are. A rather windy autumn day,
雖然風勢較大  但天色尚算良好
but a pretty good day for a launching.
適宜進行下水禮
Any day is a good day
這季節任何一天也適宜下水禮
for a launching in these times.
我們的揚聲器已安放在重點位置
Our microphones are in several key spots.
可以為各位報導典禮的盛況
為什么停車
What's holding us up ?
當然是交通擠塞
Traffic, buddy. What do you think ?
我要徒步好的
Here. I'll walk. Okay.
典禮快要開始了
The main speaker is about to begin.
我要交給主禮臺上的唐倫
I am now turning you over to Bill Donnan, located on the actual platform.
這艘巨型的戰艦
Go ahead, Bill. This is Bill Donnan.
在我們面前
We're located right below the bow of the great ship.
像只龐大的怪獸般
It towers over us like some enormous monster.
我們身處的主禮臺
This platform--
帶我去見負責人
Take me to the guy in charge !
我來應付他你想要什么
Okay. I'll take care of this.
下水禮會有事發生  是破壞
What do you want ? Something's gonna happen. Sabotage.
你從何處得到這消息
Where'd you get your information ?
我不能詳細敘述  沒時間了
There isn't time !
你最好到辦事處跟主管講
We gotta have more to go on.
我告訴你  沒時間了
Better tell the chief.There isn't time !
你想我怎么辦
What do you expect ?
帶我去見下水禮的負責人
Take me to the guy in charge of the launching.
你要通過辦事處才可以
You gotta go through the office first.
這是命令
Towley, 1 050.
現在人山人海  海軍軍官齊集
Crowded with all kinds of navy officers and personnel.
在左邊的是皮雅斯將軍及夫人
I can see Rear Admiral Pierce and Mrs. Pierce.
皮雅斯夫人會在主持破瓶禮
It is Mrs. Pierce who will perform the bottle breaking.
她正在下面跟來賓握手
She is shaking hands with a great many people down there.
各位
Just a second.
皮雅斯少將正步向麥克風前
I see Rear Admiral Pierce moving toward the microphone.
看來開始致辭了
Yes. He's going to begin his speech now.
我們接駁到致辭者的揚聲器
We'll switch you over to the speaker's microphone.
在戰爭期間一艘戰艘下水
The launching of a ship in time of war...
是一件莊嚴的事情
is always a solemn occasion.
今天我們的部隊
Today, when our fleet is fighting on all the seven seas,
正在戮力作戰
this ceremony gains magnitude...
這小伙子去哪里了
for it represents a victory. Where'd that guy go ?
我不知  他只是沖出去
I don't know. He just stepped outside.
這是代表美國人民的
by the strong hands of American workmen.
在此刻  我們齊來慶祝
- Let us rejoice, then, at this moment.
我們要有信心
Let us be confident,
他們為國捐軀
Our American soldiers...
令我們可以
are freely giving their lives so
和平地安全地生活
that we can live in decency, security and peace.
我是唐倫  大家已聽到了
This is Bill Donnan again.
是皮雅斯少將在海軍基地的演辭
You'vejust heard Rear Admiral Pierce speaking from the Brooklyn Navy Yard.
比利
His speech is being received with great applause--
快鎖上后門
Shut the back doors ! Quick !
她快要下水了  預備拉擎
I can handle this ! Be ready to pull out as soon as she goes.
海軍軍官正將一瓶香檳交給她
The officer is handing her a bottle of champagne.
群眾很緊張  這是莊嚴的典禮
The crowd is tense. It is indeed a solemn occasion.
我用揚聲器接收現場的聲音
I switch you over to our microphone near the bow of the ship...
會放在船頭位置  大家可聽清楚
so that you may hear the actual launching.
我見到皮雅斯夫人正步向船頭
I can see that Mrs. Pierce is moving towards the bow.
將麥克風交給皮雅斯夫人
I'll switch you over now to Mrs. Pierce.
我憑藉美國人民之名
In the name of the people of the United States,
為阿拉斯加號施洗
I christen thee Alaska.
發生什么事
What's the trouble ?
我不知  某處發生了爆炸
Don't know. An explosion somewhere.
佐治
George !
一切順利嗎
Everything okay ?
不  快幫手  我們捉到一個人
No. Give us a hand. We got a guy.
要分頭走  穿過走廊及鐵閘
Better scatter. Go through the iron door into the music hall.
帶他進音樂廳  我們這邊走
We'll go this way.
趁佐治來捉我們之前  快走吧
You must go at once, before Henry catches you here !
你不是要令那老家伙妒忌嗎
I thought you wanted to make the old boy jealous.
不要吧  他說見到你便要殺死你
Not anymore. He's threatened to kill you on sight.
他不會那么過份吧
You don't think he'd go that far, do you ?
你要趁早走啦
Oh, will you go before it's too late ?
趁他射殺你之前走吧
Before he shoots you ?
你說老亨昨有手槍
Old Henry's got a gun ? A real gun ?
你以為這是什么
Oh ! What do you think this is ?
我終于捉到你了
I've caught you,
你這混蛋
you rat in the grass!
走吧  韋伯  別讓他射中你
Stop that! Run, Wilbur! Before he gets your range!
快出來  否則我再開槍
I think I got it now. Get out before I shoot again !
走吧  韋伯
Run ! Quick!
他碰不到我的
Never touched me!
今次射中了
I'll get you this time.
走吧  韋伯  他又開槍了
My husband ! He's shot !
我的遺愿是要殺死他
I'll kill the rat if it's the last thing I do !
我發誓  我只不過是開玩笑
He was only kidding. I swear ! And I'm only kidding too !
快滾出來
Get outta here! Get outta here!
來吧  滾出來
He's gone mad! Mad!
不是這樣  他會殺死你的
- Get out! Get out! -
謀殺呀  救命呀
Not that way! He'll kill you!
走吧  快逃命
Murder! Help ! Run ! Run ! - Run for your life! -
他在這里
There he goes !
他是你要捉的人
He's the one you're after !
你才是
You're the one we're after.
我告訴你  是他  他快逃走了
Come on ! He'll get away !
你坐車去跟蹤他  這是唯一機會
Come on ! Grab a cab and go after him. It's our only chance ! Taxi !
到市中心哪里
Downtown. Whereabouts ?
隨便去哪里  只管駛往市中心
Anywhere. Just keep goin' downtown.
可否換些零錢打電話  好的
May I have change for the telephone ? Yes. ma'am.
接線生  請接往聯邦調查局總部
Operator ? Give me the F.B.I. headquarters, please.
聯邦調查局  請等我替你接線
Federal Bureau of Investigation. Hold on, I'll put you through.
要確保他不能搭下一班船走
Make sure he doesn't leave by the next boat.
跟他談話  跟蹤他
Talk to him. Follow him !
盡量拖延  直至我們到來
Keep him there until our men come along.
那女孩說跟蹤到富禮去庇利島
She thinks she's traced Fry to Bedloe Island.
她是瘋子  他從未去過那里
He'd never go there !
你上月在何處捉到史高斯
Where did you pick up Schultz ?
在博物館  展覽現代藝術的地方
In that museum, that modern art place.
連拿度呢  在看金魚時拘捕他
And Renaldo ? You caught him in the aquarium.
對  最后在自由神像附近擒獲
But the statue's a dead end.
正是了  他很狡猾
He's smart. Get going.
捉他回來  可告他很多罪名
Get going.
但愿那女孩沒有弄錯
Let me take him to make sure the girl hasn't made a mistake.
布克  你最頑強  由你去
Burke, you're one of the most obstinate men I've ever met ! Get going.
請問布連在哪里
Pardon me. Could you tell me which is Brooklyn ?
我們似曾相識嗎
I've seen you before, haven't I ?
一定見過
Sure.
是在那艘船
On that boat comin' over.
你問我什么
What'd you ask me ?
我素仰布連大名  想知道在何處
About Brooklyn, where it was. I've heard so much about it.
在那邊
Over there.
你來自何地  紐約
Where are you from ? New York.
你為何兜搭我
What are you handin' me ?
我在市中心的商店工作
Oh, no. You see, I work in a store downtown.
沒時間到處逛
I never get a chance to get out.
整天呆坐店內  沒時間去游覽
I just sit around all day, and I never see anything.
我對自己說過  首次外游
So I said, the first vacation I get,
一定要去看看自由神像
I'm going to see the Statue of Liberty.
對你來說定是難忘的時刻
This must be a big moment for you, huh ?
是啊  現在對我們很有意義
Oh, it is. And it means so much to us now.
我剛看過這小冊子
Why, I was just reading in this booklet.
你知否它是法國人帶給我們的
Did you know this statue was given to us by the French ?
知否上面寫著什么
You know what they had written on it ?
將你的疲累及貧窮的人民交給我
''Give me your tired, your poor, your huddled masses...
他們盼望能呼吸自由的空氣
''yearning to breathe free;
那受到污染的海岸
''the wretched refuse of your teeming shore.
將那些無家可歸的暴徒交給我吧
Send these: the homeless, tempest-tossed to me.''
那些法國人真凄慘
And just look at the French. Isn't it sad ?
對  很凄慘
Yeah. Ver sad.
這神像真美麗
Oh, it's such a beautiful statue.
我會整天坐著靜思  你會嗎
I could just sit up here all day thinking about it. Couldn't you ?
改天或許會  今天不行
Some other day, maybe. Not right now.
我現在要趕搭那班船回去
Right now I gotta catch that boat back.
你會跟我去嗎
You comin' ?
下一班船十五分鐘后便到
Well, there's another boat in 1 5 minutes.
不如稍后吧  所有人離去
Couldn't we wait ?
便可讓我倆單獨相對
All the people have gone, and we'd be alone-- just you and me.
聽起來很寫意
Sounds cozy.
但我要趕時間
But I-- I haven't got the time.
秋色如意
Oh, on a nice autumn day like this,
你不能陪我片刻嗎
you couldn't spare 1 5 minutes for me ?
我不喜歡秋天
I don't like autumn.
你對我這孤單的女孩太無禮了
You're not being very nice to a lonely girl.
我看你也很孤單啊對
You look as though you might be lonely too. Yeah.
我要趕搭那班船
I gotta catch that boat.
一刻鐘有何分別  富禮先生
Fifteen minutes shouldn't make such a big difference, Mr. Fry.
你是誰
Who are ya ?
別再假裝了  你是誰
Come on. Quit stalling. Who are ya ?
我已跟你說過  我今天休假
I think I told you. A working girl on her day off.
別耍我吧
Don't kid me !
你在這里做什么
What are you doin' here ?
富禮先生  這是個很長的故事
It's rather a long story, Mr. Fry.
是從一個不知名的金發男子開始
It all started with an unknown blonde,
是一個來自加州的飛機廠工人
an aircraft worker at a factory in Glendale, California.
我明白了
I get it.
拿著火炬的自由的小女神
Little Miss Liberty, carryin' the torch.
你為何要跟蹤我
Why'd you follow me ?
還在想什么  若仍不明白
Why do you think ? Take a look down there.
可看看下面  他們來捉你了
If you can't figure it out, they're coming for you.
你見他在人群里嗎  不見
Do you see him in this bunch ? No.
班尼斯  你在這里看守
Barnes, you stay here and watch this end.
其他人跟我來
You fellows, come with me.
你倆  看守這邊
You two, watch that side.
我要上去
I'm going up.
巴利柏  他在哪里
Barry ! Pat. where is he ?
他往下面走
He started down !
你肯定嗎
Are you sure ?
他在上面  來吧
He's up here ! Come on !
來吧  富禮
Come on, Fry !
我會抓著你的衣袖
I'll get your sleeve.
別去  若失足便?人同歸于盡
Don't you go over ! If you slip, that'll be three gone !
快去拿繩索來
Quick ! Get a rope.
沒有踏腳點嗎  我不能
- Can you get a grip with your feet ? - I can't.
支持住  我們拿繩索來
Kane, I'm getting a rope !
他們拿繩索來  你要支持啊
- They're getting a rope. Hold on, Fry.
我發誓  會替你澄清
- I'll clear you. I swear I will.
我會令你清白
- I'll clear you.
快拿繩索來
- Hurry up with the rope !
叫他們快些  那衣袖
Tell them quick. The sleeve. Sleeve !
堅尼
Kane !